Witches
Witches.
Since time immemorial, these beings have
always stood at the pinnacle of sorcery:
the original 17, known as the Origins,
and the mighty lineage that inherited all of
their magical power, craft, and knowledge.
These descendants are the witches of our age.
Witches sometimes aid people
and sometimes curse them.
So how can one undo a witch's curse?
1. A loving kiss from Prince Charming
One way is a loving kiss from Prince Charming.
Another is if the wrathful witch
has a change of heart.
2. If the wrathful witch has a change of heart
And...
Damn it, Ashaf.
She'd better really be here.
Of course she's here. Although...
Whether she's the one you're looking for...
That's another story, Guideau.
The Witch and the
City of Blazing Red
A witch?
That's right.
If you're looking for the witch,
you should start with her.
Are you the witch?
He's looking for the witch.
Oh, is that why you're visiting the city?
Where is she?
Tell me where the hell she is!
Guideau.
I beg your pardon.
My friend has a short temper
when it comes to witches.
You see, she has unfinished business with one.
Oh, really? What's she look like?
Dunno.
But we're certainly lucky to find
someone who knows the witch so soon.
I wouldn't call it "luck" at all.
I'm not the only one who knows Lady Witch.
Everyone in the city knows her.
I doubt you even need to ask around.
How do you mean?
Fire!
Well... That's certainly quite the beast.
Must be a powerful spellcaster
to control or become such a thing.
Hah! Already showin' themselves!
It's the witch!
Not at all.
You've got it all wrong.
That's not who you're looking for.
You there...
Could you hold this for me?
Y-Yes, Lady Witch.
Detain him!
Amazing, Lady Ione!
What do we have here?
Quite the celebrity, I see.
Of course. She's the city's hero.
A hero witch?
There's no question about it.
You seem happy to say that.
What student wouldn't be happy
to see their mistress succeed?
That so?
I'll head over first to introduce you.
Well, that explains that. "Lady Witch," huh?
At least we wasted no time finding her.
Guideau, our mission comes first.
No acting on impulse...
Oh, my.
Lady Ione, as usual, thank you for your help.
You're our city's guardian angel.
You give me too much credit.
Mistress!
Marie, are you done shopping?
I'm sorry. I got distracted by all the chaos.
I'll be sure to get everything later.
After all, tonight's the big night.
Don't you all remember
what those witches did before?
You're out of your mind
to treat her like a hero!
Mark my words, I'll kill you myself one day!
Shut up! Hurry up and take him away.
I've found you, you damn filthy witch!
Huh? You...
Damn it! You bitch!
I know you've seen my face before!
You know her?
I'm not too sure.
Shut up, you liar!
That's enough!
You messed with the wrong person!
I dunno what made you believe in this bitch,
but witches bring only
disaster and misfortune.
You're all gonna die if this shit continues!
You little...
Wh-What?
Get off!
Good grief. It always goes like this.
You need to leave it to me and stay back.
Shut up, Ashaf! You're not the boss of me!
My sincere apologies.
Was this the plan all along?
It's all a misunderstanding.
We bear no enmity. But...
Seeing as how you're a witch,
we'd like to have a few words with you.
Screw you!
You're the one who attacked her!
Hurry up and arrest them, too!
They look suspicious enough!
We will take our leave quickly, Guideau.
What? Screw that!
The witch is right there in front of us!
Lady Witch, excuse us,
but we'll call at another time.
Our regards to you, too, little miss.
What was all that about?
Roughly 400 years ago,
a wicked witch cast a curse on the city,
turning it into a doomed land
consumed by hellfire.
But the wicked witch was defeated,
and the curse was sealed.
The curse was sealed?
That's the supposed history of this city.
This castle is where the curse
is said to be sealed,
as well as being the current
residence of our witch.
Or so says the pamphlet.
How the hell can a witch live in public like this?
That's how much support she's gained in 400 years.
Bullshit.
Sure, to you, all witches are evil.
But I suppose it does raise some questions.
Oh. Did you two get invites, too?
Not exactly. We have business with Lady Witch.
Are we interrupting something?
Well, there's a party tonight
for the anniversary.
Oh? The anniversary of what, exactly?
Thanks for coming, everyone! Come on in!
What are you two doing here?
Picking up where we left off.
Now, let me through.
I told you to stay back and keep quiet.
I'm afraid not!
There's no way I'm letting
bad people like you near my mistress.
Huh? All witches have a screw loose!
Why would you get so worked up defending one?
That's exactly why I won't let you near her.
In the past, this city treated witches
terribly because of the wicked witch.
To atone for this, my mistress
devoted herself to helping the people.
She protects the city from
disasters and criminals abusing magic,
saving many people in the process.
Including me.
Years of hardship finally bore fruit,
and she ended discrimination against witches.
That's why I won't let her near anyone
who berates her simply because she is a witch!
My, how heartwarming.
Really, that was quite moving.
But I can't say I recommend
believing everything you hear.
What do you mean?
The story of that sealed hellfire.
It's supposedly a witch's curse, but...
That doesn't quite add up.
A witch's curse is never something
that can just be "sealed."
So if it really has been sealed,
that makes it irrefutably
something other than a curse.
Which raises some curious questions.
How could I believe any of that?
I don't assume you would.
But our world is filled with hidden truths.
So I'm saying, just as you don't trust us,
you shouldn't put too much trust in her, either.
Every beautiful rose has its thorns.
And witches always come with
two things: secrets and danger.
That's enough! Stop talking as if my
mistress is plotting some evil scheme!
How unbelievably rude. Leave now!
One last thing.
This anniversary that's happening...
What is it for, exactly?
I couldn't tell you. Only my mistress knows.
Great. We'll have to force our way in after all.
Sorry Guideau, but there's
something I need to research.
Let's head back to the hotel.
Hopefully, it's nothing,
but this is a witch we're facing.
Better to be safe than sorry.
Wow, they're so beautiful!
I've never been here before!
Mistress, the pair from earlier were just here.
Oh? Did you turn them away?
They were talking about you like you
were evil, and I couldn't stand for it.
Is that so?
This is bad.
The place where the fire was sealed...
The meaning of today's date...
A witch... And the true history buried in the past.
"Anniversary," huh? Just as I thought.
I wanted to go about this amicably
for a change, but no chance of that now.
I'll let you focus on your mission.
There they are! Stop right there!
Lady Witch has requested that we arrest you!
That man's a mage. If you see
any strange movements, open fire.
Takin' orders from a damn witch?
They are known to captivate
people's hearts, you know.
But this proves it, unfortunately.
Lady Witch is indeed evil.
My, my. You are such hard-working folks.
That goddamn witch!
I swear I'll sucker punch that face of hers!
Huh?
Did I doze off?
Mistress, what in the world has...
Don't be afraid.
You're just becoming keys for me.
I snuck a spell into your bodies
during your training.
What spell? Keys for what?
To release the hellfire that sleeps in this city.
B-But why would you...
The wicked witch who once cursed this city...
She was my grandmother.
What?
Except that she wasn't a wicked witch.
You see, she sealed away
the blaze and saved the city.
The cause of the fire remains a mystery.
But witches got blamed for all disasters.
That was an immutable law back then.
Because of that nonsense,
my heroic grandmother was murdered,
and as a witch, I endured
countless attempts on my life.
Tell me, could you forgive that?
N-No. It's monstrous.
But you're being monstrous too!
Please stop this! If we reveal the truth,
we can surely find a better...
I can't let this day pass me by.
This day, exactly 417 years
since the seal was put in place,
is the one day its power weakens.
I've spent 120 years waiting for this day.
Look.
The first lock opens.
What the...
Today marks the ultimate anniversary!
I've got you now,
ya stinkin' witch!
Given your lack of skill,
I'm amazed you dared to challenge me.
Or did you have another goal in mind?
Oh dear.
I would have liked to at least
free the girls serving as keys.
Forgive me. I should have been
clearer with my warning.
You seem to have caught on to my goal.
Just who are you?
Good question.
Who could we be?
Everyone has something to hide.
Especially from witches.
So you must not open
your heart to a witch. Not ever.
That's called "prejudice."
Prejudice? What's prejudiced
about this disaster?
Prejudice caused this hellfire.
I'm told the "wicked witch"
was burned at the stake.
I'm only giving as good as she got.
You have no right to criticize.
You're just lashing out!
All the people who deserved
your revenge are long gone!
Everyone in the city adores you!
You've done so much for this city.
And all your time with us...
What was it for?
Revenge isn't logical.
I spent all that time just
laying the groundwork.
Gaining your trust made
breaking the seal far easier.
N-No...
Getting revenge on someone whose face
you can't see is like killing an insect.
Knowing and befriending you all
allowed me to appreciate you as targets.
And look at the result.
Watching you suffer...
gives me such satisfaction!
Revenge feels so sweet!
Stop! Don't unlock any more!
I hate you all more than I can bear!
I know exactly what you mean.
I hate witches like crazy!
What a resilient girl.
I'm dying to bash your brains in right now,
but you haven't given me a straight answer yet.
Take a good look!
Do you recognize me?
Or this mark?!
Oh, I see. That mark...
You want to undo a witch's curse, don't you?
Though I don't know why you're
going about your search this way.
But I see. So you want to be sure.
A witch's curse, once cast,
is so difficult to remove
that it's become known as
the "eternal malediction."
There are only two ways to undo one.
First, "a loving kiss from Prince Charming,"
meaning a heartfelt kiss from
your partner in pure, mutual love.
Second, "if the wrathful witch
has a change of heart,"
which means getting the one
who cursed you to undo it.
But I'm sorry to tell you that
I'm not the witch you're looking for.
So I can't undo your curse!
I don't know which witch
you have me confused with,
but you wasted your time.
You're wrong in one respect.
You don't need to be the witch
who cast the curse to lift it.
Third...
"Kiss a witch."
There are more than two ways to break a curse.
Wha...
What?
Ah, nothing beats being in your own body!
What is this menacing aura?
I don't sense any powerful magic, and yet...
Is this her true form?
I hope you're not too rusty, Guideau.
I'm about to find out!
How about this?!
Aren't you going to help?!
Regrettably, I'm a mere first-rate mage.
I'd be of no help at all in this battle.
Besides, I'm not needed.
You see, Guideau is the most beautiful
and most terrifying of creatures,
and the witches' greatest
and only natural enemy.
Why?
Why doesn't she stop?
Brace yourself...
for a gut punch!
What is... this monster?
I see they're finally getting
the fire under control.
Another dead end, damn it!
Such a shame.
This method only lifts the curse temporarily.
To truly break it, we really need to find her.
I see more collapsed over there!
Are you okay?
For better or worse, I guess you
can't judge people by appearances.
Who are you people?
Bringing witches back to the Order is our job.
The Order?
It tackles all manner of magic-related trouble.
Our group works by magic, for magic, and of magic.
That's us, the Order of Magical Resonance.
Now then, Guideau, let's hurry home.
You're the one wasting time, jackass!
Mind your language.
I'll find her and kill her.
This is revenge.
Next time:
"The Witch's Pastime: Opening Act."
The Witch's Pastime
Opening Act