Forbidden Instruments.
Merely possessing these sorcery tools
grants might approaching that of a witch.
Forbidden Instruments
Sorcery Tools
But while their wielders gain power,
Payment
they must make sacrifices in payment
or else forfeit their lives.
Thus, the use of Instruments
is strictly forbidden.
Sacrifice
Yet those who turn to them
are never in short supply.
For you see...
What was that sound?
Did you hear something?
Yeah.
I'm going home.
If you're worried, I can walk you.
I'll be fine. It's not far.
Goodnight.
There sure are a lot of crows.
Not yet. It's still not enough.
I've got to add more.
The Witch's Pastime
Opening Act
Hey. Is there a witch around here?
Beats me. They're supposed
to tell us the details in person.
So how can we be of service?
Please keep this between us,
but the master of the house
has a penchant for collecting.
And I'm ashamed to say that a specimen
has escaped from his collection.
Escaped? So it's an animal?
Yes, sir. And quite a violent one at that.
It has claimed many victims already.
Since you called in the Order,
I assume it's not just a rare creature.
Don't tell me you have a magical beast here.
Yes.
As you say, the creature is magical.
So you want us to subdue it?
You are to recapture it with the
utmost haste, and without harming it.
Without harming it?
I see. That explains why you're struggling.
Hm? Where are you going, Guideau?
I'm done with this bullshit.
Now, now. We're on the clock.
As if I care about a plain old beast.
You can handle the pet-sitting.
Dear me.
Who do you think you are, a king?
Excuse me. Pardon the intrusion.
Matter manipulation is the
most basic of magic spells,
but controlling fluids
requires a particular knack.
Honestly, I've always struggled with it.
You're full of it.
You wound me, Guideau.
It's not nice to call people liars.
Will that do?
Splendid work.
I was right to call on you.
We're honored.
Magical beasts are illegal
in this country, you see.
I wanted to handle this quietly.
I heard that you'd take on any job,
and I see that info was correct.
Oh, not quite.
We only stick our noses into magical trouble.
We're a group that works by magic,
for magic, and of magic.
If you have any more difficulties,
call the Order of Magical Resonance.
Treating oneself after work
sure hits the spot.
What's wrong? Not eating anything?
Gimme a break.
Tell me what our last job was, jackass.
We apprehended a petty burglar who had
committed heinous crimes using magic.
Quite a good deed, if I do say so.
And before that?
We exterminated a ghastly tree
that fed on magical power.
And before that?
Let me think...
Oh, yes. A stalker abusing magic—
Before that?!
Babysitting a young magical beast.
Are you screwing with me?
What the hell do you think
I joined your shitty Order for?
You don't need to remind me.
Oh, dear. That was good wine.
Hurry up and find me a witch!
If you can't do that,
the Order's a waste of my time.
You must realize that cases
involving witches don't grow on trees.
And our relationship is give and take.
In exchange for our full support
in achieving your goal,
you agreed to serve
at the Order's discretion.
We get priority when witch cases comes up.
So until one does, do your job.
If you slack off like you did today,
we won't give you witches,
fine food, or anything else.
You didn't need me today, anyway.
True enough.
Excuse me, sir.
I was asked to give you this.
Thank you.
It's from the Order.
Is it a witch?! Gimme!
How many times must I tell you? You need
an Order signet ring to break this seal.
Although you should have
one of these brands, too.
Oh? Cheer up, Guideau.
Speak of the devil.
A witch!
This lady is merely our client.
So where's the damn witch, then?!
We're with the Order of Magical Resonance.
I believe you have a job for us?
I'm sorry to have you come
all this way. Please come in.
I can't seem to open this case anymore.
Can you do something about it?
I see. A runic inscription.
You're in luck.
Spellpicking is my specialty.
Goodness.
Another good deed done.
I live for people's smiles.
Get ready for what's coming to you, asshole.
I never said anything about a witch, did I?
You should have realized that
when I left the coffin behind.
Then what was that
"Speak of the devil" about?
I was just saying that you should
take non-witch cases seriously.
Bullshit!
If you feel you were fooled,
consider it a learning experience.
It taught you a lesson.
Like hell I will.
Trusting you was my big mistake.
"Mistake" is another word for "experience."
They're both shortcuts to wisdom.
Sorry, but we don't have time to quarrel.
There's a job waiting for us.
Hope for better luck on this one.
I'll let it slide, but only for the time being.
As soon as my curse is lifted
and I don't need the Order anymore,
the first thing I'm gonna do is kill you.
Glad to hear it.
I'm looking forward to that day myself.
A peaceful, witch-free month
has passed since then.
What a tranquil afternoon.
I'd say the day you reclaim your
real body is still a long way off.
I'll kill you later,
but I can always kick your ass now.
Temper, temper.
Anyway, eat your fill.
Good, isn't it?
It's gross as hell.
For you, mister.
From the Order again?
Yes.
More busy work, I bet.
To hell with that crap. Rip it up.
No, you'll like this one, Guideau.
It came in a black envelope.
So what?
They only send these when a witch
is involved and central to the case.
It seems a witch is committing serial
murders in Hayden, the capital of Pheres.
They even make a point of
calling the case "grotesque."
Besides which—
Enough. Gimme.
You're so impatient.
We're about to be busy.
There's an ocean between us and this case.
Pack your bags.
So a witch and a grimoire?
We won't have an easy time of it.
Ms. Haines, it's dangerous!
My children are in there!
Shulk! Loran!
You were groaning in your sleep.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
If you say so.
Sorry. She gave us the slip again.
How many dead?
At least five.
And the bodies were...
"Consumed, sacrificed,
or something similar by a witch"?
How could anyone do something
so horrible? She must be crazy.
"Crazy," huh?
I've seen plenty of perps with a screw loose.
They all had one thing in common.
Know what that is?
No.
Unfulfilled desires born
from a sense of inferiority.
Losing control of them can turn even
upstanding people into crazed villains.
You mean no person is born evil?
"Person," huh?
Is a witch a person?
Beats me.
But witch or human,
anyone who can do this must be scum.
I couldn't agree more.
We didn't expect this fight.
Is that why you didn't set
all your barriers in time?
You mean she wouldn't
have escaped if I'd finished?
Er, no.
Closing off the scene would've made
no difference. She slips through barriers.
What I meant was—
I know.
We need to box her in to make
her cast as many spells as possible,
or we'll never figure out her magic.
But even if we solve that mystery,
it's just the first step.
The full force of the Hayden Police
still has to take this slow and steady.
A feeble police force can't
fight a monster any other way.
Ms. Haines, I shouldn't have to tell you
that this goes way beyond
regular serial murder.
You're the only mage we've got.
If you feel powerless, talk to the mayor.
Witches are the Paladin Corps' jurisdiction.
Unless something changes,
the body count will just keep growing.
I know.
I know that.
I know it's easier said than done,
but try not to beat yourself up over
what happened to Inspector Cole.
I've handled plenty of horrific cases.
I thought people always
remembered the perpetrators
and forgot the victims in no time.
But then someone murdered
people I cared about,
and I realized that I'd never
forget the names of either.
Don't worry. I'll do my job.
Oh, dear. It appears we're too late.
Don't give me that crap.
You let her slip right out from under us.
Cut me some slack.
And rest easy. The witch
in this case will be back.
Grotesque mass murder committed by
a witch, a.k.a. the "Witch's Pastime" case.
As of last week, the victims
numbered 36, including police officers.
Quite a tough nut to crack.
What did tonight make the body count?
Who are you people?
You know how to test my patience,
so you must know who I am.
And you look suspicious.
What's in that coffin?
Peppering us with questions already?
Well, I can't blame you.
Rest assured, we're perfectly respectable.
So please, stay your hand.
We mean you no harm.
In fact, we'd like to help you.
Help how?
We're with The Order of Magical Resonance.
A major incident is disturbing your city.
If you suspect a witch is responsible,
then we have much to offer you.
Hayden Police.
We'll take a table in the back,
but I'd like to set a soundproof barrier.
S-Sure.
I got confirmation.
It seems the mayor really did
sign off on a request to the Order.
I would never lie to a beautiful lady.
By the way, could you hold off on that barrier
until we've received our order?
Of course. At least let me
have a cup of coffee.
No, please wait for our full meal.
Replacing barriers is a hassle, no?
For our part, we'd like to hear
about the case as soon as possible.
Tell me your story first.
The mayor might trust you,
but I certainly don't.
But you have a witch case on your hands.
Sooner or later,
the Paladin Corps will step in.
But for some reason,
the mayor is stalling them.
Making you our only hope?
Looks that way.
To begin with,
this whole situation is strange.
Police forces aren't
equipped to combat witches.
What you need is an army.
That's why global peacekeepers
like the Paladin Corps handle witches.
The mayor is probably refusing their help
to claim the glory of
solving the case without them.
Anyone can see how foolish that is,
so why do you all go along with it?
As the force's only mage,
I believe you're in charge of the case.
You ought to protest. Why don't you?
Who gives a shit?
Just tell me everything
you know about the witch.
Then I'll kick all the witch ass you want.
Why are you so fixated on the witch?
Most people would steer clear
of a witch serial killer.
That's—
Guideau, have a bone.
For our organization, essentially.
We cover all magic,
which includes witchcraft—
Don't hide anything unless
you want to lose even more trust.
I came up with this barrier myself.
Lies can't fool me in here.
Asshole.
Dear me. How shrewd of you.
Answer me.
Well, our circumstances aren't worth hiding.
We just want to undo a curse.
A curse?
A witch's curse. You must know of them.
Sure. Anyone who's even
dabbled in magic does.
Then I'll be brief.
My friend here has one of those.
So we're looking for the witch who cast it.
And more or less at random,
since we have almost nothing to go on.
That's not all.
I'll find her and kill her.
This is revenge.
Revenge...
We can't be lying, right?
Right.
No, I believe you.
It's a very selfish reason,
but I can trust it more than
some great and noble cause.
Oh? You need to use reasoning?
I thought you could tell if we were lying.
That was a lie, actually.
I can't cast a spell that good.
What?! Screw you!
All right, fine.
I'll work with you.
We start tomorrow.
Meet here at 9 AM.
Hey, did she just...
Make us do all the talking? Why, yes.
Now, shall we go see a witch?
Next time: "The Witch's Pastime: Final Act."
The Witch's Pastime
Final Act