The Witch's Pastime:
Final Act
We suspect a witch, based on
the overwhelming power.
Then there are the messages
left at the crime scenes.
Each one points to the killer being a witch.
Oh? Such as?
"I live on and on without change.
I bear heir after heir without change."
Do you know what that points to?
A witch. Witches don't age
and their health doesn't decline.
And a witch's power is
passed on to her descendants,
so even having children doesn't change th—
What is it?
The killer wants to declare
that they are a witch.
I bet all the answers are "witch."
What about this one?
"Four legs in the morning,
two legs at noon, three legs at night."
A witch.
A human, I believe.
Right. A human.
How strange. Was that one of the messages?
That's right. None of it
means much of anything.
The killer's playing with us.
We call it the "Witch's Pastime" case
because it's all a game to them.
But that game has come back to bite them.
I realized that some of the riddles
were taken from a book.
A book that was ordered from this bookshop.
Even the timing lines up.
I'm impressed you traced the source.
I just got lucky.
I have the same book at home.
It reeks.
What do you think you're doing?!
You guys go in.
Damn it!
The wound shows magical damage.
It seems natural to conclude
that a witch inflicted it.
She must have gouged out his eyes
because he was a witness.
An attempt at irony, I assume.
If she intended to cover her trail this way,
why bother leaving messages in the first place?
I told you. It's just a game to her.
She probably just decided
she might as well kill this guy, too.
We've lost our lead.
You look exhausted.
Perhaps you could use some rest?
You shouldn't get too close to me.
Why not?
Because of precedent.
Nothing good happens to people I'm close to.
What is it?
Ms. Haines, we've found another body over here.
And a message.
What's it say?
I'm a disease.
Diseases propagate and spread.
This disease is called a curse.
A witch's curse.
I took you to the scene,
but you didn't find out much.
Oh, well. Corpses aren't my specialty.
Well, I'm not expecting much.
See you.
Ashaf.
Yes?
Get ready. Something's here.
Really? You must be joking.
I left the coffin at the hotel.
Idiot! Don't just rush in blindly!
She disappeared!
In a puff of smoke, quite literally.
So she's powerful and an escape artist, too?
I'd say we have our work cut out for us.
Still, why would the witch...
She was tailing her.
What?
Ever since we met up with that woman,
I've felt someone watching us.
Looks like I wasn't imagining it.
Shit!
I'd like to ask you something.
What happened to you?
We had a little run-in with the witch.
And you lost her?
Yes, completely.
I see.
There goes what little hope I had for you.
You took quite a beating.
I've already treated the wounds.
More importantly,
please answer my question.
How are you connected to the witch?
What?
It seems you were followed.
The witch must know what you look like,
so we can safely assume
she tailed you, not us.
Why does the witch make a point
of announcing what she is?
Presumably to mobilize the Paladins.
Who likes fighting small fry?
But no matter how long she waits,
only the police oppose her.
So to draw out the Paladins...
Guideau, what would you do?
Kill all the small fry.
Or...
take out their boss.
The mayor's egotism caused this situation.
But only insiders know that.
Most would assume the police would be
lost without you, their only real fighter.
And yet, despite all of that
as well as shadowing you,
the witch waited until we split up,
and then targeted us.
Why?
Why won't she go after me?!
Why follow me if she
doesn't want to kill me?!
I don't know. That's why I asked.
Don't tell me...
Could it be...
So you do know something. Cough it up!
This case, needless to say, had a beginning.
I don't often see you this early, Kiera.
I always run late. If I don't go home early
and eat with the kids when I can,
what kind of mother am I?
Ms. Haines!
What is it?
Your house just...
Ms. Haines, it's dangerous!
My children are in there!
Shulk! Loran!
Were there any witnesses?
Local residents have given us information.
And we think the culprit left a
message on a wall across the street.
"I live on and on without change.
I bear heir after heir without change."
What could it mean?
A witch.
It's the time that was on the warning note.
Yeah.
Damn it! Not this purple smoke again!
We can't get a clear view!
Everyone, take shelter in the barrier!
Reuben, what are you doing?!
I'll take her down.
Alone? That's crazy! She's a witch!
Yes, I know. The witch who killed those kids!
I lost my sons and Reuben.
He was my magic teacher... and my boyfriend.
I suspect that warning was meant to...
What you told me clinches it.
It was to lure him to his death.
The witch is targeting people I care about.
You got too friendly with me.
So we gave her the wrong idea, huh?
But that clarifies things.
The witch has a vendetta against you.
Any idea why?
Of course not.
But that's perfect.
If she's hung up on me,
I may get a shot at revenge.
Revenge, huh?
I see. So that's why you went
along with the mayor's lies.
Do you blame me?
I put my revenge ahead
of the lives of citizens,
and keep racking up needless sacrifices.
I don't have the sense of duty
and justice a detective should.
I won't fault you, but are you certain?
You look miserable.
Don't talk like you understand.
Even if you do get your revenge,
who will celebrate it?
I know!
I know I'm not strong enough,
and that no one wants revenge.
I don't need you to tell me that!
But I still can't do anything
about this pain... this hatred.
What the hell?
You keep spouting crap that makes no sense.
If you wanna get even, just do it.
Who gives a shit who you do it for?
You said it yourself.
You'll kill her 'cause you hate her.
You'll kill her 'cause you want relief.
Revenge feels great.
Wh-What do you...
I'm not like you!
Why would you encourage her?
Ms. Haines!
The witch has sent a warning!
She's coming to the station in three days!
Goodness. She must want to
kill someone there at any cost.
Can I trust you?
Can I really trust you to
measure up to the witch?
Damn right you can.
I'll teach you...
what makes revenge so sweet.
The witch's main spell is purple smoke.
I don't know how it works.
She can crush most things with it,
or send them flying.
It also acts as a smoke screen.
What's even more concerning
is her vanishing magic.
By the way, what did you do
with those leather sacks I got you?
Oh, this and that.
About Guideau... I know what she said,
but if we manage to beat this witch,
will that soothe the dead a little?
Yes, I'm sure it will.
She's late.
I've already digested everything I ate.
Give us a time of day, too, asshole.
How are you feeling?
Huh?!
What are you, some street thug?
Anyway, how on earth do
you plan to fight the witch?
Shut up and watch.
Once I undo the curse on me,
this witch will be a pushover.
Wait a minute!
Don't tell me you're counting on that?
You must know how to undo a witch's curse.
You either kiss your true love, or get the
witch who cast the curse to undo it. That's it!
Can you prove this witch
is the one you're looking for?
'Course not.
Don't worry.
You see, there's actually one
more way to undo the curse.
That's what we're betting on.
If we face a witch and meet certain
conditions, we'll see the return
of a monster even witches fear.
She's here.
I see her.
Get ready!
Don't jump the gun, Guideau.
Huh?
Good grief. Rampaging right out of the gate.
What's that sound?
Watch out! She's up to her old tricks!
What just happened?!
Given how little we can see, we can't
attack recklessly because we have allies.
But our opponent is free to cut loose.
Hardly an enviable position.
Is everyone all right?
Yeah. We can manage as long as
we focus solely on staying alive.
Guideau!
That asshole!
Thank goodness.
We kept our losses to a minimum.
This sucks. Just let me kill her ass already!
What good will fighting do when
our enemy has a way to escape?
We strike after we have her cornered.
We've done everything you've said so far.
You'd better have a plan for what comes next.
Not a problem. I've already located her.
How could you have...
Have you noticed that
there are more crows lately?
Those are my familiars.
And I can borrow their eyes
to see what they see.
There's no escape for her now.
Now, shall we go see a witch?
Huh?!
Honestly. Must you charge
in alone every single time?
Ashaf, there were two of 'em.
No, forget that. Damn it!
These assholes aren't witches at all!
Tch, another one. How'd they find us?
Dude, you survived?!
Yes. Did you think you'd killed me?
Well, of course you would,
after a rampage like that.
Unfortunately for you,
I'm confident in my barriers.
Damn. This guy's a mage.
Are you two alone?
What's going on here? It can't be...
You're alive, Shulk? Loran?
Ah, crap.
You're the last person we wanted to find out.
You know them?
They're my sons.
The ones I told you the witch killed.
But how?
What are you doing here?
Don't tell me...
There's no way!
Loran...
Shulk...
You two were the witch all along?
No, that can't be.
I know you don't have that kind of power.
Look at what they're holding, Kiera.
There's the truth behind
their witch-like power.
The two-volume grimoire, Sarnouasuth.
A grimoire?
Grimoires provide power and
perform spells for their wielders.
No magical prowess required.
Just holding one grants power
almost on par with a witch's.
They're a type of Forbidden Instrument,
which are taboo tools of dark magic.
And either part of a two-volume grimoire
can summon its other half
instantly across space.
But only up to a distance
of roughly one kilometer.
So I was able to locate them
in next to no time.
Who is this guy?
Where did you get something like that?
What are you talking about?
They were on your desk!
What?
You have no right to punish us!
It's your fault we ended up this way!
We don't kill because we like it!
These grimoires give us power,
but we have to feed them lives!
They'll eat us if we don't
give them sacrifices!
Touching the grimoires made us this way!
So we had to kill!
No...
That's a good one.
I saw the corpses you left behind,
you definitely enjoyed every moment.
You had to? You had no choice?
Then...
Then why did you kill Reuben?!
He loved you both, too!
That's enough.
We don't owe you all the answers.
And this is a fight to the death!
Unfortunately for you,
there are three reasons why
you stand no chance against us.
Huh?
First, you failed to pay
your grimoires' price.
What are you talking about?!
I know we killed at least ten people today!
We made our sacrifices!
Oh, you mean these?
What the hell is that?!
A mere dummy. Red liquid in a leather sack.
Well, they don't stand up to close inspection,
but your smoke made it awfully hard to see.
So what?!
With this power, we can kill all we need!
I'll crush you!
Second, even with the curse intact...
we're still quite strong.
Ah, well, no need for number three.
You punks don't have what it takes
to call yourselves witches.
Assholes.
Why did you pretend to be witches?
So we wouldn't have to fight you.
You were too young to be our mother.
We could only see you as a woman.
We couldn't let anyone get near you, Kiera.
We love you!
You love us, too! Don't you, Kiera?!
If you won't end this,
get outta my way and I'll do it.
I'm fine.
I'll do it.
W-Wait!
Why?! You'd just abandon us?!
You said you loved us!
I did love you.
But you crossed a line.
Now I don't even pity you.
Why'd you adopt us?
Because I wanted you to know.
Know what?
What it is to love and be loved.
Ordinary things like that.
The Witch's Pastime case,
which has long tormented Hayden,
was thought to be the work of a witch,
but we have just learned that
two boys committed the killings.
Damn it, Ashaf. You knew the
witch was a fake, didn't you?
Well, you catch on quick when you know
as many dark secrets as the Order does.
Nothing would have kept the
Paladin Corps out of a real witch case.
After I destroy this food, you're next.
Now, now. Be reasonable.
Hey.
Kiera.
Thanks.
We really wouldn't have had
a prayer without you two.
Just doing our job.
And you paid us handsomely
with these grimoires.
The grimoires...
I don't remember ever seeing them before.
Forbidden Instruments
have wills of their own.
They find the right person at the right time.
You mean they got there on their own?
That may just be what happened.
They were never the best behaved of boys,
but they never would have turned out
that way if not for those grimoires.
The deaths they would have
suffered for failing to pay the price
would likely have been far more horrible.
I'll be going now.
Kiera.
Next time you run into trouble, drop us a line.
Sure.
I'll give you a call.
If a witch shows up, you can count on it.
Naturally, we retain a
necromantic specialist.
Beauty and Death
Opening Act
Next time: "Beauty and Death: Opening Act."