Only the undead can see its light.
And in the eyes of those who have lost
their reason through neglect,
it outshines all else.
I chose a deserted area to minimize the risk,
but it appears we unintentionally
hit the nail on the head.
Oh, the trail keeps going this way.
With necromancy,
no parting lasts forever.
What have you done?
What have you done?!
This will suffice for him,
but as for you, despite my efforts,
I couldn't learn a thing about you.
I'll avail myself of a bargaining chip now.
Johan!
Do as I say, and you'll see him again soon.
Now, follow me.
Um... Performing her autopsy
must be hard for you.
Why don't I take over?
There's no need.
I'm perfectly fine.
Is that so?
How hideous.
Mireille, I shall bring you back
with flawless beauty.
Beauty and Death
Final Act
Despite how she treated Johan,
she must've really cared about him.
Ah, excuse me.
This occasionally happens
when I disengage Manual.
The undead's mind fails to return.
Have a seat.
We saw plenty of other
servants on the way here.
Don't tell me they're all undead?
Indeed they are.
This isn't a one-man crime.
You must have accomplices.
Even I know that resurrecting the
dead takes a ton of magical energy.
There's no way you could have
revived this many on your own.
It is possible, even without help.
What?
Raising complete people and keeping them
that way with regular maintenance
is what consumes vast amounts of power.
Sloppy work, as we saw in that ruin,
doesn't take all that much power.
He neglected their maintenance, too.
And while these girls seem
decent at first glance,
I'm sure they're barely there inside.
Unscrupulous necromancers often do
the bare minimum for functionality.
They don't bother restoring
most of the organs or senses.
It takes hardly any magic.
Well spotted.
You know your necromancy.
The question is whether they're strays.
Of course, they're probably
all strays on Semi-auto.
I'm shocked.
Even you must know how
sinful creating strays is,
and how heavy a price the
dead pay for resurrection.
Naturally.
What price?
Normally, after death, the soul
begins preparing for reincarnation.
It flows into the spiral of transmigration,
and after a long time,
it achieves resurrection.
But necromancy rips them from that cycle.
And resurrection doesn't last forever.
When the spell eventually fades
and they die a second time,
they cannot return to the cycle.
There is no way to rejoin
the stream after leaving it.
Wandering souls go somewhere that
has no up or down. No left or right.
No motion or pain.
No light or sound or heat.
Their minds simply exist.
And that nothingness lasts for all eternity.
That hell is called...
the Void.
So all undead go there?
They all fall into the Void?
Sooner or later.
To accept death and await reincarnation,
or to regain a temporary life in exchange
for a fate crueler than death?
You deprived them of the right
to make that grave choice.
Let the undead worry about that.
It doesn't affect necromancers.
You piece of shit!
What the hell are you doing this for?!
What could justify your atrocities?!
My goal?
Let me think...
Put simply,
it's you.
I desire your beauty.
You see, I too lost someone I loved.
What beauty.
She was a beautiful young
woman with fiery red hair.
Fortunately, I had my necromancy.
Reuniting with her should
have been a simple matter.
But unfortunately, the manner of her
death burned away most of her skin.
I can produce any number
of hideous creatures.
Beauty, however, is challenging to recreate.
But I can regain what she's lost
from those that still have it.
I can supplement any
remaining deficiencies myself.
Beautiful things appeal to me.
I might as well give her the loveliest
possible body when I resurrect her.
The undead you saw were from
my attempts to hone my technique.
Some more successful than others.
That's it?
That's your only reason?
Everyone values things differently.
What do you think?
All the undead and taxidermy specimens
in this room are my successes.
I think they came out well. And yet...
They pale beside your beauty.
I do hope you'll let me
use your body as a base.
How dull.
That's really your only reason?
I played along because
I expected there to be more to it.
Ms. Kristoffel...
Such composure.
I see. Given your knowledge of resurrection,
you must be a necromancer, too.
I wondered why the undead I'd abandoned
in the cellar ran off all of a sudden.
I suppose that was your doing.
But even if you are a necromancer,
what can you do in this situation?
You abide by the rules, don't you?
As long as you're bound by them,
you cannot oppose me.
Please don't try to be clever.
Sorry...
but I'm not just a necromancer.
Those eyes!
Those runes!
No... It can't be...
A witch!
I wasted my tears.
Impossible!
How could I have unwittingly
invited a witch here?
A witch? No way.
Actually, it all makes sense now.
Since I first set eyes on her, her beauty
has seemed chilling, almost otherworldly.
So I take it we're going
to do this the hard way?
Of course.
Wait. You seem to have forgotten something.
Why do you think I took a hostage?
You can't resurrect someone
without a part of their corpse.
If I have my undead reduce him
to ash, you'll never see him a—
Suit yourself.
He won't make a good hostage.
And regardless,
I won't stop until I've dealt with you.
I see.
Then it seems I must resort to force.
"Prepare for the worst," and all that.
Thank goodness I made combat models.
Combat models?
Don't you ever stop?
I don't know how much you tinkered
with them, but they're still strays.
You can bind them with Semi-auto,
but they remain mindless automatons,
barely aware of themselves.
You can't beat me with those.
You're bluffing.
Few people wish to become undead
once they learn of the Void.
Even fewer would put themselves
in a necromancer's service or control.
But even knowing all of that,
some still offer themselves to necromancers.
With the utmost respect, I call them...
Death Knights.
None of you lay a hand on that bearded man.
As for everyone else, well...
Do as you please.
Stop!
Don't fight!
P-Please stop!
Sorry.
As long as the spell lasts, killing the
body is the only way to stop them.
I'll see to it that the
necromancer gets his just desserts.
What a miscalculation!
Of all things, why a witch?
Damn, damn, damn, damn!
How dare she ruin my plans?!
But I'm not finished.
I'll remodel your body into
the ultimate warrior right now.
Man, seriously?
What a scumbag.
What happened to all that talk about beauty?
Impossible! How are you alive?
Oh, no. I'm good and dead.
When did the witch resurrect you?
She was with me until just a moment ago!
She had no time to—
Oh, come on. What's so weird about it?
I've been undead this whole time.
But undead can't get over physical death
without necromantic maintenance.
So how am I standing here
good as new, you ask?
The answer to that should be obvious.
I'm not just any undead.
I'm a witch's undead.
S-Stay back!
Stop!
Basically...
I'm one of a kind.
Wait!
Calm down, now. Don't kill me.
Don't kill me!
If I die, all of those undead will...
Kill you?
Nah, I won't do that.
See, you crossed a line.
You broke every taboo in the book.
I... I know.
I'll take responsibility for those undead.
You pissed off Phanora.
Death's way too good for you.
S-Stop...
I'll start with your fingers.
Please stop!
I-I beg—
Johan, you...
I haven't killed him yet.
Listen.
Y-Yes?
I'm about to break the law, so could you
keep this whole incident to yourself?
What?
A promise won't do.
You'll need to consent to a contract spell.
I don't know...
The Order of Magical Resonance remains
shrouded in mystery despite its fame
because we require our clients
to watch their words.
You want me to turn a blind eye
to a crime? I could never—
Don't you want to save her?
If you want to save all the victims,
shut up and do as I say.
I'll have you maintain all the undead
you resurrected as complete human beings.
I'll provide the magical power,
so don't slack off.
What have you done?
What have you done?!
Me, undead?
How dare you?! How dare you?!
This means I'll... I'll fall into the Void, and—
Worrying about the afterlife already?
I hate to break it to you,
but I won't give you a moment's peace
while you're in this world, either.
Ms. Kristoffel, does this mean
I can see her again?
The way she used to be?
Well, yes.
Her illegal resurrection means she'll
have to keep a low profile for now,
but I know ways to legitimize her.
Is that so?
Feeling conflicted?
I guess so.
I feel torn,
but thoughtless as it is,
I can't help being happy.
Hey.
What?
You're done now, right, Phanora?
Get away from him.
You're too close.
Johan.
Yeah?
What did you do with my luggage?
Huh?
Uh, wait.
Where'd I put it?
Are you saying you lost it?
I mean, I had more important things—
Find it.
Fine.
Not even a thank you.
Johan.
Yeah? What do you want?
I'm sorry.
I spoke thoughtlessly without
realizing you were undead.
And I warned you to
"watch out for beautiful women,"
but you never had a choice, did you?
Do I look that sad to you?
You don't seem well-treated.
That figures.
But whatever.
Don't worry.
This is fine by me.
Wh-What are you doing?!
What do you mean?
That was for hurting Johan.
I haven't even had a boyfriend yet!
Next time: "The Witch and
the Demon Sword: Opening Act."
The Witch and the Demon Sword
Opening Act