The Paladin Corps
The Paladin Corps.
Serving the world's largest
state religion, the Global Holy Church,
this magical army fights for world peace.
Their mission: to resolve equally
magical atrocities of massive proportions.
No other force can handle
witch-related incidents.
But the peace-keeping Paladin Corps has
a dark side that never enters the public eye.
Namely...
Ashaf! Stop holding out on me.
What's the rush? Your food will get cold.
What lovely weather.
Maybe we should have eaten outside.
Quit stalling and give me the damn thing!
Oh, honestly. When will
you learn some patience?
You got a death wish?
I thought you said you'd kill me later.
Now, listen.
This letter describes a string of bodies
sliced to ribbons, seemingly by a witch's hand.
But I suspect this case will prove
even trickier than usual.
Yeah?
They would never miss a witch
case on the Third Continent.
Unfortunately, our mission is
to make contact with the witch,
and the Paladin Corps is
certain to stand in our way.
It'll be a free-for-all for the witch.
The Witch and
the Demon Sword
Opening Act
That tower just...
They'll destroy the whole city at this rate.
The witch is on a rampage.
The hell are all these people doing here?
Evacuating, I presume.
Drama queens. It's just a witch.
That's why they're running.
The Paladin Corps wasn't called in
for the Witch's Pastime case,
and that sloppy handling stopped
panic from spreading to the townsfolk.
This is what a witch scare
is supposed to look like.
After all, a witch can level a city
or two without breaking a sweat.
Halt. This area is off-limits.
And how come you're dressed so lightly?
We're from out of town.
And fall only just started.
Mind explaining why it's so chilly out?
There's a witch on the loose.
Anything is possible.
So when disaster strikes, blame a witch?
What was that?
Oh, nothing.
Still, this makes things tricky.
My grandmother lives alone, you see.
I can't reach her,
so I'd like to check that she's safe.
If that's the case, I could let you through,
but I'm not sure about your luggage.
Well, I suppose not.
So, could I see some ID
and what's in the coffin?
Will a brand do?
Yeah. Put it here.
A mage, huh? Thought so. Looks like
you're originally from around here.
Nothing unusual here.
Next, the coffin.
This won't be an issue.
Is that...
A church permit for this magical instrument.
It proves that there's no room
to smuggle anything in it.
If it's approved by the church,
I have no problem with it.
Hey. Escort them.
Yes, sir!
Huh? Did you lose your way?
I can get out a map, if you'd like.
Don't kill him, Guideau.
Now, let's not dawdle.
He said you were from here.
So you must know your way around.
That ID was fake, obviously.
Isn't working for the Order convenient?
My fists are pretty convenient too.
Dear me. How barbaric.
I'm cold even with a coat on.
It may snow at this rate.
Commander Cugat, sir, we're facing a witch.
How could you leave your aides
behind and challenge her alone?
Save your complaints for later.
I lost track of the witch.
Sir, facing her again
without backup would be—
Save it.
The search for the witch is in your hands now.
Once she's been located,
prioritize keeping her pinned down.
Leave defeating the witch to me.
How reassuring.
But the mission is to capture the witch.
Under no circumstances are you to kill her.
Who's that?
An emissary from the Holy Church.
Apparently, he's been investigating
this witch for some time.
He deserves the credit for
uncovering this incident so early.
But what is he doing here?
Supplying information, or so I'm told.
He must know important
details about this witch.
That's the Castle. The Paladin Corps
operates out of it while on missions.
It's built out of special materials
and surrounded by multiple barriers.
Even a witch would
have trouble destroying it.
And the barrier enclosing
this city is equally durable.
Even if we did break them, the paladins
would detect it and come running.
How the hell do we get in, then?
The witch is in there, remember?
We create a discreet opening.
A skill I happen to be quite good at.
My spellpicking would put
even a witch to shame.
You've been blessed with an
excellent organization and partner.
Quit yapping and do it already!
You can't rush these things.
What the hell?
That's...
The witch.
Ashaf! Open it already!
Don't rush me.
I almost have it.
Jeez. What's their problem?
I don't want to die yet.
I can't let myself die.
I haven't even had a boyfriend yet!
So she got them, too, huh?
Sir! My Seekers were eliminated by the witch!
Meaning she wiped out
the entire search team.
Prepare for a second sweep.
Based on data from the first sweep,
the witch creates and controls blades.
She's roughly 170 centimeters
tall and has long black hair.
We've confirmed Ultoma
around her right eye.
But I don't see how this—
It's 168 centimeters.
Excuse me?
Her height.
And her hair is black with
a red tinge, to be precise.
She prefers monotones for her clothes,
and she always carries
a tubular leather case.
Apart from that...
You seem strangely well-informed.
So maybe you know which
lineage this witch belongs to?
That's the information we need right now.
Knowing her lineage will tell us
what powers she's inherited.
He's part of the pursuit team.
Sir! Seekers destroyed!
Cause unknown!
The pursuit team was
supposed to stay hidden.
What happened?
I was monitoring the witch from
outside her estimated attack range,
but I didn't see her make a move.
It seemed like something
attacked from my blind spot.
What is it now?
Dear me.
Keep buying us time, Guideau.
I've got you now, you rotten witch!
Take a good look. Recognize my face?
As if I'd know a girl
with an evil mug like yours!
You're mine!
Well done, Guideau.
That was a long spell,
but thankfully I'm not too late.
It's compression magic.
I didn't ask.
But she can't be the bitch I'm looking
for if you can lock her up in there.
She's weak as hell.
You sure she's the real deal?
Oh, she's a witch, all right.
For reasons I won't go into,
she can't wield her full power.
I wouldn't have let you charge in otherwise.
Huh? How the hell do you know so much?
Because I do.
I recognized what type of witch she
was the moment I saw her Ultoma.
As a matter of fact,
she's the weakest witch I know of.
But she is still a witch. They'll defy
your expectations now and then.
Our expectations would be more accurate
if you didn't withhold information.
I realize I'm not welcome here.
I was worried you'd kick me out
if I told you all I knew.
But very well.
Creating and controlling weapons
doesn't require a witch to achieve.
But only one witch's mark—her
Ultoma—takes the shape of swords.
You don't mean...
She's a descendant of an Origin,
the Dauntless Witch, Quena Velvette.
Helga Velvette.
Due to a certain factor, her lineage
is extremely weak in battle.
But don't let your guard down.
I know this sounds strange,
but while she may be the weakest witch,
she also possesses the means
to destroy the entire world.
Come on. You must be joking.
Don't tell me she brought...
the Demon Sword.
Yes.
The true danger in this case
is not the witch herself.
It grants its wielder the
power to rule the world,
and brings ruin to everything else.
The witch is most likely carrying
the Demon Sword Ashgan.
Mobilize every unit you can.
If this witch has the Demon Sword,
we have no time to waste.
We'll hit her with everything.
Yes, sir!
Farmus, remain here and take
command of the Seeker forces.
Yes, sir.
And one more thing.
You want me to keep an eye on him?
He doesn't try to hide how suspicious he is,
and I doubt it's because he's innocent.
He's also a mage. Stay vigilant.
Well, I give up.
Compression magic won't be enough.
Compressing her alone took
quite a toll on my magical energy,
and I didn't count on her
having the Demon Sword.
It simply has too much mass.
That's why my spell came undone.
What the hell is this Demon Sword thing?
Is it really that big a deal?
Oh, yes. An enormous deal, in fact.
The Demon Sword can't do much
unless someone draws it.
But once unsheathed, it becomes too much
for anyone to handle, even a witch.
So it's strong as shit?
Exactly.
Stronger than me?
Good question.
I'd be fascinated to see
which of you comes out on top.
Whoa, there.
Found you.
Now, could you do something
about those annoying crows?
I'd like to talk.
No more violence.
Excuse me? Don't you think
it's a little late for that?
If you wanted a friendly chat,
you should've said so before attacking me.
And for that, I apologize.
I would have preferred other methods,
but I had no choice.
You see... How do I put this?
We don't look particularly trustworthy.
Right.
So would you honestly have
lent us an ear in this situation?
No way.
Well, there you have it.
We'd like to shelter you in a safe place.
"Shelter" me?
Yes, shelter you. You have my word.
We aren't your enemies.
We're here to help you escape
from the Paladin Corps.
Interesting.
Don't be so hard on them, Helga.
Hey!
So what if you can't trust them?
You must be ready to grasp
at straws now. So no matter what—
Ugh, zip it!
What a surprise. The Demon Sword speaks?
Why act so startled?
Swords talk. Everyone knows that.
Ashgan! Don't make me repeat myself.
You know I'm always
warning you to keep quiet.
Speech is in a sword's nature—
Can it!
May I ask you something?
I thought you descendants
of the Dauntless Witch
kept the Demon Sword under
lock and key in a secret location.
Bringing it out into the open carries risks.
I assume you have good reasons for doing so?
That's none of your business.
Right now, I refuse to trust anyone.
Then you should finish us off quickly.
Why don't you?
If you doubt our sincerity,
then we're nothing but enemies in your eyes.
This incident began with murders
committed by a witch. Six victims in all.
If you did that, then why hesitate now?
Stay back!
It appears you're not heartless
enough to kill an unarmed man.
You didn't kill them, did you?
In which case, I'm all the
more eager to help you.
What do you get out of it?
What do you want?
I doubt you're just being charitable.
This woman's life?
Fine. Take it.
Don't speak for me!
Whatever they want, don't refuse them.
Accept their terms.
It will be more fun that way.
What a rude interruption.
Here comes the second wave.
What the hell are these guys?
The paladins' avatars, essentially.
Destroying them won't
do much to the paladins.
They'll resupply with magical energy from
their base's tanks and come back for more.
So they just send in an endless supply
of soldiers that don't stay dead?
Yes. That's the Paladin Corps's
standard playbook during a witch hunt.
Against the Seekers' guns,
two layers should suffice.
Hurry! This way!
Take his hand and stay with him.
You can't survive alone.
Sorry, but I have to go it alone.
I don't need your help.
But...
Thanks anyway.
I'd call that a rejection.
Hah! Serves you right.
Why are you talking like
it's not also your problem?
Go after her.
I trust you understand, Guideau.
What?
She's not the witch you're after.
So switch gears and focus on
our mission to bring her back.
Protect that witch for all you're worth.
I don't need you telling me to do my job.
What a stubborn girl.
Still, I'll enjoy seeing just how long
you can bear your solitude.
Shut up! If it wasn't for you, I'd—
This chill...
Yes.
It looks like he's here.
Enough of this pointless struggle, witch.
I've made up my mind not
to let you get away again.
Well, well. A paladin flesh this time?
Then you'll stay dead when I kill you.
Everyone loses themselves
in pursuit of my power.
The Witch and
the Demon Sword
Act II
Next time: "The Witch
and the Demon Sword: Act II."