Huh? Did you lose your way?
I can get out a map, if you'd like.
Don't kill him, Guideau.
Come here, Guideau.
You come here.
Recognize the insignia?
Nope.
Good grief. You really have no interest
in anything but witches, do you?
Armies normally rely on strength in numbers.
Against witches, in particular,
having an elite few makes no sense.
They require a quantity
so vast, it seems infinite.
But annoyingly, this force
is built not on numbers,
but on overwhelming individual might.
If you encounter someone
who looks like their commander,
don't assume you can beat him.
The Third Continent Paladin Corps's
6th Battalion is led by the "Man of Ice,"
Matt Cugat.
His power rivals that of a witch.
This must be him.
The Witch and
the Demon Sword
Act II
Stop, Guideau.
Save the kiss for later.
What? Why?
This guy's gotta be the boss, right?
If I take him out here, our job's done!
Guideau, your strength
is our ace in the hole.
We haven't gotten the
full picture of this case yet.
Always hide your ace in the hole
until all the cards are down.
For the moment, buy her time to escape.
Just concentrate on that.
Now...
I believe my attention is needed here.
What are you muttering to yourself for?
Wait, were you talking to that hot—
uh, that guy from before?
Hey! Put up a decent fight!
He'll focus on me if you go down.
I'll help you escape.
Get lost while I keep him busy.
What? But what will you do
once I've gotten away?
Shut up and move it.
Having a witch next to me
makes my damn skin crawl.
Well...
That works out great for me.
So that's the Demon Sword?
He was telling the truth.
All the more reason to finish this now.
Look this way!
I already am.
What? She lost already?
Shit.
I heard you were bad news,
but you're not even a witch. How do
you fire off spells without moving?
You surprised me, as well.
I didn't expect you to be so fast or strong.
That weapon in your right
hand must be magical.
Is it the secret to your superhuman strength?
I have a lot of questions, but you can wait.
Witches don't die easily,
even when you strike to kill.
I hope that holds true.
What the...
It really is stunning
what an elemental can do.
He's on par with a witch?
How? You mean he's not human?
No, he's human.
But he made a pact.
A "pact"?
Exactly.
Matt Cugat forged a pact with a
primordial force to rival witches:
a great ice elemental.
He's an elemental mage.
Ow.
Who is this guy?
He's practically a witch.
Ashgan! Where are you?
I'm here.
Come to me.
Thank good—
No.
Huh?
I wasn't calling you.
I meant...
you.
The Demon Sword. I'm glad I secured
it before you could try anything.
Give it back!
Really? Return a weapon this
dangerous to a murderous witch?
I know I can't beat him.
But what else can I do?
This time...
I got you!
You survived?
I bought you a few dozen seconds,
so why the hell are you still here?
You're a witch, right?!
Well, excuse me for not being much of one.
Huh?
No! Don't let them take it!
What strength.
Hand over the Demon Sword.
Hah! You want this thing that bad?
I don't really give a shit about this thing,
but you assholes aren't
getting anything out of me!
Huh?
What's wrong with you?!
Of all the pointless....
I don't believe it. She picked up
Ashgan, then let it go again.
I've never seen a human do that before.
Damn it!
You again?
Hey! Give it back!
You've got no right to carry that!
Yes, let go already. I can't stand you.
You want it? Do what I say.
Now, shut up and follow me.
Excuse me?!
We're gonna meet up with Ashaf!
Why should I listen to this brat?
Ashaf, where do you wanna meet?
So you're safe, Guideau. What about her?
She's with me, and she'll do what I say.
Come again?
Now we've just gotta get away and—
Is something wrong?
Hey! Run like hell!
Wha—
Is he trying to freeze the whole city?!
Move it! He's gonna catch up to us!
Over here!
What's your plan?
Once we're through here, no matter what,
don't let go of my hand!
Hey, what's with these puny-ass spells?
Never call them "puny" again, you hear me?
I hate that word.
You always say a woman's size isn't every—
Shut up! Both of you!
What?
You're kidding me!
What am I supposed to do against that?
Pontevert.
This city in the south of the Third
Continent is blessed with great weather.
The food is delicious, too.
On the house.
Goodness!
And passionate men.
My witch blood makes me such
a people magnet, it scares me.
I love this town.
Six corpses were discovered
in the city early this morning.
All six bear cuts from
some kind of edged weapon,
and the wounds show signs
of extreme magical corrosion.
Reports suggest a single killer
using powerful magic.
The victims are all people I met yesterday.
Ashgan, did you do something again?
What could I do, sealed away like this?
But, Helga, if you want to
make me do something...
Draw me, Helga!
You have no other way out this time.
Unless you draw me, you'll die.
Save your breath, Demon Sword.
The witch can't move.
An elemental's protection?
I don't like you, either.
Put the witch and her ally in Armor.
I doubt you've ever been put in Armor before.
It hits pressure points that restrict
the release of magical energy.
The perfect restraining
device for witches.
Come to think of it,
didn't they have an accomplice?
And quite a skilled one,
according to the reports.
Quite skilled? You're too kind.
You're astonishingly powerful yourself.
I'll be in a real bind if you cart off
those two and the Demon Sword.
Is that so?
Too bad for you, then.
Take them to the Castle.
I'll take care of this one.
I'll rendezvous with the commander.
Take the witch and her friend to base.
I suppose I can't stop you from taking them.
Still, this works out well.
I was hoping for a word with you.
What?
I have a good eye for people.
Matt Cugat, the Man of Ice,
you strike me as the type to listen
to an argument in good faith.
Don't give me that.
You obstructed our mission,
and now you talk about "good faith"?
Speaking of that mission,
don't you think it smells fishy?
A witch and six victims.
Each has a convenient witness,
and the witch committed every murder
with her magical swordsmanship?
If a witch simply wants to kill a human,
she has so many other ways of doing it.
She's practically asking you
to send her to the gallows.
A taunt like that shows true confidence.
A typical witch, you might say.
Fear of witches may have lessened,
but it remains deeply rooted in society.
People are so on edge that
a witch just being near a death
is enough to create a "witch incident."
Framing a witch for a crime is simple.
No hard evidence is required.
And that's just what happened here.
Someone set a trap for Helga Velvette.
What?
I'll teach you to put me on ice.
Don't think a trick like that
will keep me asleep for long.
Nothing can imprison me
except a witch.
Oh, no!
What are you doing? Don't struggle!
Stop! Don't touch the Demon Sword!
Don't even look at it!
What's gotten into you?!
Let go! It's mine!
Enough! Stop! That doesn't belong to you!
It belongs to me!
It's begun.
Even sealed, the Demon Sword's immense
power tempts and captivates people.
Once it takes hold,
the temptation spreads like ripples.
Everyone loses themselves
in pursuit of my power.
Mere humans can't help themselves.
The problem is that woman.
Why isn't she tempted?
What in the world is she?
What is all this?
What's happening here?
You seem to be having trouble.
Allow me to sort this out.
I instructed you to remain
in the command center!
That goes for all of you!
I didn't order you to deploy seekers!
Stop! Have you lost your minds, too?
Ashgan?
No. Humans tempted by Ashgan
aren't so well-organized.
Open fire.
Someone framed the witch?
Speaking from experience,
I have a good idea who.
It's their oldest trick, after all.
You couldn't know about them,
but you do share a connection.
This group targets all witches,
good and evil alike,
and uses any means to
hunt them to extinction.
The dark side of the
righteous Paladin Corps.
A secret force of witch hunters:
the Executioners.
I knew this would happen if you
brought the Demon Sword here
without knowing what to expect.
So, all according to plan.
Even amid all this chaos,
I can create loyal soldiers who won't fall
under the Demon Sword's influence.
With this Forbidden Instrument.
Now, where's Helga?
Where could she be?
Find her.
The Executioners set up this witch incident?
Yes.
Impossible.
The Executioners epitomize the Dark Ages.
A detestable product of a millennium ago.
The survival of the dark side would
never make it into the history books.
Due to my work, I know the Holy Church
at least as well as you do.
I can't prove the Executioners
orchestrated this.
I'm merely speculating
based on experience.
But are you sure my theory
doesn't ring any bells?
Did no one approach you with a smile
plastered on their face, posing as a helper?
You said you were speculating?
Yes. Nothing more.
You're talking nonsense. At least, for now.
Yes. For now, that will do.
Come in, command center.
What's wrong? Come in!
Does it sound a bit less like nonsense now?
Since you house a great elemental,
I wasn't sure I could run you through.
But thank goodness.
I see you're still weak to heat, Commander.
Lowell...
Harming you provokes the
great elemental's wrath, yes?
Now that you've learned too much,
you won't make such a good pawn anymore.
Then again, I believe he always
planned to dispose of you.
Apparently, being so
righteous and by-the-book
made you harder for the
Executioners to make use of.
He said you're perfect for
sending against witches,
but still not worth as
much as the Demon Sword.
Heartless, don't you think?
Goodbye, sir.
I have nowhere left to run
and no way of escaping.
This is it for me.
My life is going to end like this,
slandered as a serial killer.
Ah, I so wanted a boyfriend.
What a nimble girl.
Vice Commander, I'll let you handle her.
I wonder who you are.
You can tell me the whole story later.
Stop!
Oh? So that's where you were, Helga.
Helga.
Draw me.
It's only a matter of time
until I'm unleashed now.
If you can't avoid it, then the
smart choice is to draw me yourself.
Drawing me is the only way you can survive.
True.
That man wants the Demon Sword.
And in the shape I'm in,
I won't be able to resist
telling him how to unleash it.
But I won't let that happen.
Anyone but me needs something
to draw the Demon Sword,
and they'll never get it if I die.
As long as I die, you won't be
able to have things your way.
I wanted a boyfriend.
I wanted to be happy.
I don't want to go out like this,
but there's no way I'll abandon my duty now!
I keep the world safe
from the Demon Sword.
That's the whole reason I've had
such rotten luck all this time!
How is she moving on her own?
Does my control have no effect on her?
Is she really human?
Hey! Cast some kind of spell!
I can't yet. I only just got it off.
Naughty, naughty.
The witch and the Demon Sword?
What a greedy girl.
Hey! What the hell are you thinking?!
Go! Forget me and protect the Demon Sword!
Like hell I will!
I've gotta take you with me,
or I've wasted my time!
Then rescue me.
If bringing me back is your job,
keep the Demon Sword safe!
Come back and rescue me!
As if that'll ever happen.
Quite right.
I know everything there is
to know about you.
Hope doesn't suit you.
This base and the witch are now mine.
And soon, the Demon Sword will be, too.
There's never been any hope for you,
and there never will be.
I've gotten by on my own all this time.
No one's coming to save me. I have no hope.
I know all that.
Now, shall we show our own ace in the hole?
Next time: "The Witch and
the Demon Sword: Act III."
The Witch and
the Demon Sword
Act III