Hey! What the hell are you thinking?!
Go! Forget me and protect the Demon Sword!
Like hell I will!
I've gotta take you with me,
or I've wasted my time!
Then rescue me.
If bringing me back is your job,
keep the Demon Sword safe!
Come back and rescue me!
As if that'll ever happen.
Quite right.
I know everything there is
to know about you.
Hope doesn't suit you.
This base and the witch are now mine.
And soon, the Demon Sword will be, too.
There's never been any hope for you,
and there never will be.
I've gotten by on my own all this time.
No one's coming to save me. I have no hope.
I know all that.
Hey, are you Ashgan?
I kind of figured the Demon Sword
would look like a bigger deal.
The Witch and
the Demon Sword
Act III
Without Helga, lifting my seal is impossible.
Turn back at once.
Shut up.
I don't take orders from you.
I'll drag that damn witch back
even if it leaves her spitting up blood.
Where are you going? She's up there.
What do you expect me to do? Fly?
I'm gonna meet up with Ashaf.
Oh, so you can't cast even one little spell?
The wall has disappeared.
So they fought to a draw.
You'd better not have died on me, jackass.
Hi there, Guideau.
I'm delighted to see you escaped.
As you can see, I...
Well, I'll be fine.
He saved me.
Still breathing, I see. I'll begin treatment.
Huh? What for? Just leave him.
Guideau, did an Executioner show himself?
Yeah, he did.
I convinced him they exist.
He'll help us fight.
So they left me alive. Barely.
Why did you hold back?
That can't have been the extent
of a great elemental's power.
Magic comes in all types.
Did my subordinate willingly betray me,
or was she controlled?
I couldn't be sure.
The elemental would have killed
her if I hadn't restrained it.
That wasn't the only time.
You pulled your punches quite a bit
against Guideau here, too.
Matt Cugat, for a "Man of Ice,"
you're surprisingly soft.
That soft heart will get you killed.
I know I sent that girl and
the Demon Sword to base.
And I don't see the witch.
What happened up there?
An Executioner took over the
whole Castle. Your unit's done for.
Talk about pathetic.
I see.
Now, the Executioners
want the Demon Sword,
so they'll most likely track it straight to us.
Meanwhile, we have
one man at death's door,
and a mage using up the last
of his own magic to heal him.
We'll never manage to prepare a major spell.
Then can't we at least hide
the Demon Sword somewhere?
I doubt that would work.
The Demon Sword would draw someone to it.
What the hell?
Don't draw people here, asshole!
Unfortunately, I have no say in the matter.
So what it all comes down to is...
Struggling won't do us any good at this point.
What's this? I expected you
to scurry around out of sight.
I even mobilized all these
forces to hunt you down.
I feel a bit embarrassed.
Mind control.
So that's what your Forbidden
Instrument does, Executioner?
Hm? Oh, yes.
That's right, Commander.
Seventeen ancient kings, the ablest leaders
of a great but long-vanished nation,
had their skins sewn together to make this:
the Demon Hand Ishlingen.
And by placing a royal ring
imbued with mystical power
on the right index finger, a symbol
of authority, I enhance its effects.
One brush with this hand makes
everyone do whatever I tell them to.
But it seems that no amount of caressing
will make it work on a witch.
What a dilemma.
I've overused its power,
so I think it's time I paid the price.
Don't!
I suppose this is the downside
of using Forbidden Instruments.
Don't let her get away!
What happened to not having anything ready?
A makeshift spell like that
hardly counts as preparation.
Take Helga and run, Guideau!
I don't know if I'll be as much
help to you as you'd hoped.
I see we didn't even need to go back for you.
Oh, were you planning a rescue?
Cut the chitchat.
Now, get running!
Behind you!
Watch out!
"No amount of caressing
will make it work on a witch."
Forgive me.
That was a lie.
Sorry, I guess.
You did save me a bunch of times,
even if it wasn't out of kindness.
Sorry for wasting all that.
Well done, Helga.
Come here.
In the proper hands at last.
Now...
Stop! Don't draw it!
Think this through!
If the Demon Sword
does what the legends say,
why did the witch refuse to draw it
when she was in so much danger?
Because it could have taken things
in an even more horrible direction!
Oh, do pipe down.
Surprised?
Simply unsheathing the
Demon Sword means nothing.
I know all there is to know
about the Demon Sword.
For instance, her clan, the Dauntless Witches,
kept the Demon Sword under strict guard.
So why was she roaming around
with it in a place like this?
Naturally, I know the answer.
Because their hidden refuge burned down.
They were all forced to give up the
sword's secrets, then slaughtered.
The lone survivor, Helga, went on
the run to protect the Demon Sword.
And how do I know all this?
Well, I'll tell you.
I know because we Executioners were there.
You...
You!
Whoops! My control slipped.
Witches do put up quite a struggle.
Now, at last, let me tell you
what you most want to know.
Stop!
Don't you draw me!
Lifting the Demon Sword's seal requires...
a witch's heart.
Damn you!
What the hell do you think
we did all this crap for?!
Don't you dare let her die!
Now, come! I have released your seal,
Demon Sword Ashgan!
Helga.
Stop this, Helga.
How many times must I tell you?
Leave the Demon Sword asleep
in the basement. It's dangerous.
Don't carry it around.
Don't you realize how important
our family's duty is?
Only you and I inherited witch powers,
so show some responsibility.
But...
I mean...
What was that?
Stop!
Mom, stop it!
What's going on?
What in the world could have...
Big Sis—
You were hiding,
so you must still be sane, Helga.
If you've got the Demon Sword,
just take it and run.
This placed is doomed.
They...
Mom called them "Executioners."
Everyone went crazy because of them.
They even got to Mom.
Listen. No matter what,
don't give them the Demon Sword.
You have to protect it.
I'll be a decoy or whatever
you need to get away.
So please. Do this for me.
Oh, dear. She won't say a word.
My teacher warned me not to take away
too much hope or inflict too much despair,
but I have trouble
striking the right balance.
Listen. I'd at least like to know one thing.
Even if you won't talk,
I have my Forbidden Instrument.
Someone else, like your mommy, will
tell me all of the Demon Sword's secrets.
So why did you try so hard?
You know, Helga...
Sealing the Demon Sword
to keep the world safe,
and working so hard for outsiders
we've barely even seen...
It never really clicked with me.
But we still put our lives on the line.
Never throw that away.
Do you hate them?
If you crave vengeance, draw me.
I want to get back at them.
I want to kill them all.
But I'll never draw you.
My mom and sisters would never want that.
Not even if you are in danger?
I still won't draw you.
Who knows what horrible things
will happen if I let you loose?
What just happened?
Don't tell me... that was a slash?
Yes, it sliced them.
And not just the city and the
Castle, but the wards, too.
It didn't decipher the spell.
It tore the Paladin Corps's barrier
apart by brute force.
So this... is the power to destroy the world.
I'm convinced.
This is the Demon Sword.
Magnificent! What magnificent power!
Demon Sword! Start by
putting an end to Matt Cugat!
Executioner.
You're laboring under a misconception
about the Demon Sword's nature.
A misconception?
No, I understand it perfectly.
"It grants its wielder the power to rule the
world, and brings ruin to everything else."
Mere superstition, I know.
Whoever wields the Demon Sword
gets one thing: a guarantee of survival!
The sword can strike anyone
except the person who drew it.
It's a privilege, but that's all.
I gain nothing else.
But no matter.
I have this Demon Hand that will
make the sword my loyal servant.
This Forbidden Instrument
bends even witches to my will,
and I've already sacrificed a
hundred of Cugat's men with it.
Both witches and the Demon Sword possess
power beyond human comprehension,
but the same can't be said for their minds!
And I'm telling you that's a misconception.
The witches locked away two
things: power and bestiality.
I know a little about the Demon Sword
from before it was sealed.
Besting so many witches with
that hand made you conceited.
Stop!
That Forbidden Instrument acts on
reverence and awe for those in power,
amplifying those feelings to the
extreme before playing on them.
But in its natural state,
the Demon Sword has no rationality.
It has only a body and an
impulse for sheer destruction.
How can you brainwash a monster
with no sense of reverence or awe?
This is the Demon Sword's true nature.
No human can hold a candle
to the monster you've unleashed.
Great elemental,
take my left, too, if you want it.
But don't let anyone else die.
My mind control doesn't work?
No, that can't be it.
Sacrifices! I need more sacrifices!
That must be the answer!
Hey! What's going on? I thought
you could control the Demon Sword!
Why do you think I went along with your plan?!
Do something about—
Hey!
More. I need more sacrifices.
So many more.
The Demon Sword can't touch me.
I can try as many times as it takes.
I'll just add more sacrifices and come back.
Oh, I know.
Where did the townspeople run off to again?
Go on. Rampage to your heart's content,
Demon Sword Ashgan.
Ashgan.
Have you come to?
I broke the seal, didn't I?
Yes.
That's it, then.
I can't stop Ashgan.
Hurry. Leave me and run.
You'll be better off far away from me.
Ashgan...
must carry one hell of a
grudge against my family.
In the end,
I failed in my duty,
and now I guess I'll die here.
What a letdown.
If only... If only...
I could've at least gotten a kiss at the end!
You've never kissed anyone?
No! Is that a problem?!
Hey. Fix my legs, too.
I can't walk right.
Guideau, it appears
all the cards are down.
We only expected the Paladins,
but a great elemental and
the Executioners turned up.
And then the Demon Sword slipped its bonds.
Anyone and everyone has joined the game.
So what do you say we show
them our ace in the hole?
Helga.
Would you permit us to
grant that wish of yours?
Huh?
Wait, what?!
Now, close your eyes.
Huh?! Hold on! Not so fast!
No! No way! I mean, not that I'd mind...
But, um, when you say
you'll grant my wish,
do you... really mean it?!
Yes, of course.
I mean just that.
Power great enough to destroy
the world is hardly unique.
Next time: "The Witch and
the Demon Sword: Final Act."
The Witch and
the Demon Sword
Final Act