My mind control doesn't work?
No, that can't be it.
Sacrifices! I need more sacrifices!
That must be the answer!
Hey! What's going on? I thought
you could control the Demon Sword!
Why do you think I went
along with your plan?!
Do something about—
Hey!
More. I need more sacrifices.
So many more.
The Demon Sword can't touch me.
I can try as many times as it takes.
I'll just add more sacrifices and come back.
The Witch and
the Demon Sword
Final Act
Ashgan.
Have you come to?
I broke the seal, didn't I?
Yes.
That's it, then.
I can't stop Ashgan.
Hurry. Leave me and run.
You'll be better off far away from me.
Ashgan...
must carry one hell of a
grudge against my family.
In the end,
I failed in my duty,
and now I guess I'll die here.
What a letdown.
If only... If only...
I could've at least gotten a kiss at the end!
You've never kissed anyone?
No! Is that a problem?!
Hey. Fix my legs, too.
I can't walk right.
Guideau, it appears
all the cards are down.
We only expected the Paladins,
but a great elemental and
the Executioners turned up.
And then the Demon Sword slipped its bonds.
Anyone and everyone has joined the game.
So what do you say we show
them our ace in the hole?
Helga.
Would you permit us to
grant that wish of yours?
Huh?
Wait, what?!
Now, close your eyes.
Hold on! Not so fast!
No! No way! I mean, not that I'd mind...
But, um, when you say
you'll grant my wish,
do you... really mean it?!
Yes, of course.
I mean just that.
Blood's filling my mouth,
so I can't tell what
my first kiss tastes like.
But wow. A man's lips...
sure are soft.
Huh? What?
What is this awful chill?
Even the Demon Sword has stopped dead.
What on earth are we in for now?
What's going on?
Where'd that guy come from?
Guideau.
I'd prefer to take the Demon Sword alive.
Don't use your right hand.
Don't tell me he's going to fight!
Of course. Someone has to put a stop to this.
It's impossible! Why do you think
the Dauntless Witches kept it sealed?
We weren't kidding when we
said it can destroy the world!
There's nothing it can't cut if it tries.
The Demon Sword Ashgan is
a blade that slices all creation!
Yes, I realize that.
The Demon Sword has immense power.
We've established that beyond doubt.
But you see...
You have one thing wrong.
It's not one of a kind.
Power great enough to destroy
the world is hardly unique.
Not in this world of ours.
It's on its guard?
The great elemental is warier of this
man than it is of the Demon Sword.
Demon Sword...
You must feel the same way.
Just like the great elemental,
something unfathomable about this man
fills you with fear.
Now's my chance to finish it!
It unleashed even more power.
Could it be...
But of course.
The Demon Sword was just unsealed
for the first time in centuries.
Of course it had lost its edge.
So we've yet to witness
what it's truly capable of.
So it's strong as shit?
Exactly.
Stronger than me?
Who can say?
But I'd be fascinated to learn
which of you comes out on top.
Don't worry.
I won't hit you with a right.
Now...
Grit those teeth!
Ashgan,
I'm going to seal you now.
Damn you.
You'll remain conscious
but unable to move.
You'll live out an eternity of impairment,
denied even of sleep, Ashgan.
You tricked me, Quena?
Yes, I tricked you.
You did too much killing.
I can't make excuses for you anymore.
I'd like to let you die quickly,
but the others don't want that.
I'd like to let you die,
but I also want you to suffer.
I feel torn between hating you
and another emotion.
I pray that my children, at least,
inherit the feeling that isn't hatred.
I'm surprised.
There's enough of the city left to recognize.
I never dreamed someone would exist
who could stop me so quickly.
Still...
Thanks to them, I was spared killing you.
No matter how much danger I brought you,
you refused to draw me to the bitter end.
Nothing goes my way with you.
Helga...
What an extremely
headstrong woman you are.
It's the end of the world!
Calm down! Please remain calm!
We're safe here, aren't we?!
Yes. Rest assured,
we have wards protecting us here.
The sky split apart, the earth quaked,
and the city is in shambles.
What the hell is going on?
We've lost contact with base, too.
Hey, look!
Help me!
Let me in!
Guideau, straight ahead.
Whoops. He started running.
One millimeter to the right and three down.
As if I can aim that precisely.
Oh, right. You lack your
other body's dexterity.
Well, then, just pray he doesn't die,
and go to town.
S-Stop...
P-Please, no more... Stop...
Tell me, Executioner.
Why did you need to attack us?
If your orders were to
retrieve the Demon Sword,
you could easily have carried
them out with fewer sacrifices.
Not my mission. It was my personal goal.
Matt Cugat is inflexible,
and his elemental may
protect him from mind control.
That left one option:
take the sword by force.
I wanted the Demon Sword.
I spent such a long time trying to get it.
But I'm not the only one
who covets the sword's power.
Other Executioners! The Holy Church!
They all have their sights on it!
If Cugat retrieved the sword,
it would never make its way to me again.
So I...
I see.
I believe Executioners
typically operate in pairs.
Given that his partner hasn't appeared,
he doesn't seem to be lying.
And this appears to be all he can tell us.
Executioners have their lips
sealed with contract magic.
We can't hope to get more out of him.
The only remaining use for them
is to bear responsibility
for this unmitigated disaster.
But the Executioners
belong to the dark side.
They don't exist, so arrest them as
the true culprits and nothing more.
Oh, but of course,
you don't need them alive.
After a magical battle on this scale,
no one would be surprised
to find them finely minced.
N-No, wait.
Please wait, sir! You have it all wrong!
I was only being used!
You called me soft, didn't you?
Yes. You are.
You're right. I am soft.
My form of justice won't
permit a good person to die.
Or an evil person to die while
they might still turn out to be good.
So I try to keep everyone alive as long
as I can, no matter who they are.
But...
Once someone crosses
the line, I have no mercy.
Even so, the people I lost were soldiers.
They died in the line of duty.
I believe they took your family from you.
What do you want to do?
Nothing much.
I'm as sensitive as the next person,
and I've had all I can stomach.
I don't want to see any more.
If you finish the job, do it elsewhere.
I see.
I do have one request, though.
Make them hurt so bad that
they wish they'd never been born.
Understood.
He left without even asking
who you shady guys are.
He must have some inkling.
We have a tacit understanding
with the Paladin Corps.
Sparks that might ignite
a war are strictly taboo.
So he feigns ignorance.
Why?
Because an all-out war between
us would annihilate the world.
You've got to be kidding.
Oh, well. Too late for second thoughts.
You'll look out for me, right?
Yes, of course.
We can guard you like a precious gem.
But we'd also welcome your help,
if you should feel so inclined.
My help?
You're after a witch's power, right?
No can do, then.
Most of my power goes to Ashgan's seal.
I can only actually use
a teeny bit of it, so...
Oh, right. I won't need the seal anymore.
Guideau only threw left-handed punches.
A monster of the Demon Sword's
caliber must have survived them.
And our organization
should be able to repair it.
It will take some time,
but the sword will revive.
I'm sure the world would
be better off if it died.
I thought that would've
been better for Ashgan, too.
But what do you know? It's alive.
Ah. This is a curse.
Hey, are you Ashgan?
I kind of figured the Demon Sword
would look like a bigger deal.
Hey, can you hear me?
Hello!
Thinking back, I realized it the
moment I first set eyes on her.
Is it sleeping?
Actually, can it even talk?
But I couldn't bring myself to admit it.
Stop this, Helga.
Leave the Demon Sword
asleep in the basement.
It's dangerous.
But... I mean...
Don't you feel super bad for it?
It was a big, scary sword.
People used to call it a disaster.
But now it looks like this,
and all it can do is roll its eyeball around!
And how can I "leave it asleep"
when it can't sleep?
It just stares at the wall all day, right?
And it's all dusty!
You've gotta feel bad for it!
See here? Look at all the dirt
built up in these grooves!
I get it, all right? Just put it back right now.
Hey, there's even more dirt here.
Enough, Helga.
Being so earnestly pitied by a little girl
probably stings worse than anything.
You said it.
It's laughing.
That was a laugh?
Maybe it's one of those things, like when
you get so scared, you start laughing?
Oh, so it's laughing because it blew its top?
C'mon, say something for yourself!
She's making a fool of me,
yet I don't feel even a twinge of anger.
Hey! Are you listening?
Are you not even capable of saying "thank you"?
She could be Quena's double.
And something that isn't hatred...
Must I accept it at this point?
No, never.
This is a curse.
A witch's curse. It must be.
Long time no see.
I've missed you.
Next time: "Origin Witch."
Origin Witch