I see.
I believe Executioners
typically operate in pairs.
Given that his partner hasn't appeared,
he doesn't seem to be lying.
Make them hurt so bad that
they wish they'd never been born.
Understood.
You'll look out for me, right?
Yes, of course.
We can guard you like a precious gem.
But we'd also welcome your help,
if you should feel so inclined.
Origin Witch
Hey.
Hm?
I missed my chance to ask earlier,
but did I have my precious first kiss with...
Huh?
Was there always a door here?
No. Not until just now.
But never mind that. You were saying?
Never mind. I'd rather not know.
So what is this place? The infamous
Order of Magical Resonance's HQ?
No way, right? It's way too small.
You're right. It isn't.
For starters, we don't have a headquarters.
At least, not one that anyone knows about.
This is an entrance to the Corridors.
Helga, this route is just for us,
so that I can escort you safe and sound.
Huh.
Anyway, I'll be right back.
Be good and wait here, Guideau.
Patch me up. Moving like
this is a pain in the ass.
You'll only be waiting.
Why do you need to move?
Are you sure about leaving her behind?
Yes. The Order demands
confidentiality on several points.
I know you agreed to a magical
contract to keep our secrets,
but Guideau refused.
As such, the Order's inner
workings remain off-limits.
All the more reason not to risk leaving her.
I can't see her sitting tight
and staying out of trouble.
Don't worry.
Following the mission and my orders is the shortest path to Guideau's goal,
and Guideau knows it.
Really?
My partner is more rational
than you might think.
We shouldn't need to worry
about pointless mischief.
Then again, Guideau has been known
to act on instinct despite knowing better.
A few exceptions fall into that category,
but I hardly expect one to turn up
in a country town like this.
A witch!
I saw her! I saw her! A witch!
For real?
Yeah! I saw her brewing some kinda potion.
She's really there!
A witch with a big cauldron!
She's brewing up poisons to curse people!
See? What did I tell you?
And you didn't believe me!
Yeah. That was our bad.
So what do we do now?
The grown-ups won't
believe us if we tell them.
We'll have to get her ourselves.
Hey!
Huh?
Did you hear something?
Hey, look!
Wh-What the...
Where?
Huh?
Where's the witch? Take me to her.
What?! Where'd you come from?!
You're not making sense!
What a pain. I'll kill you one at a time.
Make up your minds before
there's only one of you left.
W-We'll do it. We'll take you to her.
Uh, this is the place.
Huh? Y-You're going in? It's not safe!
Oh? What charming little visitors.
Oh, goodness gracious.
What the hell?
It won't move!
Your leg froze up? That's serious.
I'd better put it right for you.
Hey! What's your problem?!
Get out of my way!
Now my left arm's busted, too?
Hey, now. Stop that.
Injured people need care.
No need to act so skittish.
Customers love this ointment.
It's my secret recipe.
Dear me.
You certainly heal quickly.
This smell...
You're not a witch, are you?
Welcome back.
Will you be using the Corridors?
Yes, I'd like to.
Where do these connect to?
We're in contact with
rooms 5010, 6288, and 7006.
And room 7006 would be?
On the Sixth Continent, sir.
Yes, that will do nicely.
I have no clue what you're talking about.
This will make sense to me one day, right?
Of course. And unlike Guideau,
I'm happy to say you'll be worth teaching.
Mr. Ashaf, this just arrived for you.
Black...
What's that?
Excuse me. Wait here for a moment.
Huh?
Hey!
What's wrong?
Now, listen here. I do use magic,
but I'm still only a humble herbalist.
Calling me a witch is an insult to witches.
We're sorry.
This is so heavy. Hold it for me.
Do your fair share.
Your silly stories got us
into this mess, remember?
Oh?
My, my. So many visitors today.
Hey, where the hell did you come from?
I didn't sense you till the door opened.
Huh?
You're...
an Executioner!
You must be wondering where we are.
This is my private world.
An alternate dimension reached
by passing inside this cloak.
You can't even perceive it
unless you have the cloak on.
Your senses don't function.
I doubt you can even think clearly.
But you're special.
I'll allow you a bit of freedom.
I have questions for you.
Executioners work in pairs.
I have a partner.
He started acting strangely,
so I followed him.
But I suppose I caught on too late.
By the time I arrived,
everything seemed to be over.
You stayed at the scene, so I shadowed you.
But what a surprise.
I could never have managed it
without this Forbidden Instrument,
which lets me vanish from the world.
The Order of Magical Resonance
lives up to its reputation.
Now you see where you stand.
On to business.
I have two questions for you,
both quite simple.
Where is my little brother
and his Forbidden Instrument?
Hey, are you done now?
I'd like to chat with this little one, too.
Ashaf!
What happened? What could
have rattled you this badly?
Yes, I'm rattled, all right.
There's a witch in this city.
And not just any witch.
The "hateful witch" who cursed Guideau.
Her name is...
Angela!
You bitch!
Long time no see.
I've missed you.
Since this space isn't affecting you,
that cloak must be more
than a fashion statement.
I thought mine was one of a kind.
Oh, this? I made one just like yours.
Nice, right? It comes in handy.
Does she mean she copied it?!
This is no mere magical bauble.
It's a Forbidden Instrument!
And she recreated it,
function and all, just by looking at it?!
But the ones I make wear out in no time.
So, if you wouldn't mind...
give me yours.
Impossible! How is she standing?!
I only granted this woman
minimal sight and hearing.
She's been deprived
of all her other senses!
So how?!
They're both freaks!
Can you get in touch?
No, unfortunately. What rotten timing.
But even if I could, it wouldn't help.
It's too late for that.
The thread is already pulling.
What? What are you talking about?
A force that pulls people together.
The cursed and the curser
develop a special type of bond.
Those threads of fate
draw them to each other.
We call that the threads' pull.
While their power is in play,
I won't find it so easy to intervene.
In any case, this doesn't look good.
When I healed Guideau's body,
I left it fragile in places, just in case,
so the kid couldn't cause any trouble.
Of course, even in perfect health,
Guideau wouldn't stand a chance against her.
But in this condition,
even escape will prove difficult.
Not that Guideau would ever
try to run from her in any case.
H-Hang on! Calm down!
I'm quite calm. I sent out crows.
Flailing blindly will get us nowhere.
Regardless, you should go back inside.
Why? I'll help you look.
I've been entrusted with your safety.
And this is Guideau's problem.
I can't drag you into it.
But I owe you two for saving me.
I've gotta take you with me,
or I've wasted my time!
Then rescue me.
If bringing me back is your job,
keep the Demon Sword safe!
Come back and rescue me!
So just this once,
Guideau's problem is my problem.
She means a lot to you, right?
Yes, a great deal.
Far more than my own life.
Funny, isn't it?
I wanted to see you,
but not that guy who's always with you.
So I hid in this town,
and spread rumors the Church, the Order,
and the townsfolk would brush off.
Rumors only you would
take seriously, Guideau.
Just a few tall tales.
And look how perfectly that little
bit of scheming worked out.
We can see each other anytime,
as long as we both feel like it.
Fate's handy that way.
So, Guideau...
How does it feel, using my body?
A witch's flesh is all about adaptability,
so I bet it adjusted to your soul
and made things a lot easier for you.
Hands off.
You don't like being touched? Even though
you have no problem throwing punches?
Talk about picky.
You look so upset.
Do you hate me?
You know, I was playing with
someone else until recently,
but maybe I got bored.
It just wasn't much fun anymore.
Tell me, Guideau...
Is it about time we went at it for real?
That was a close one.
You were going for a kiss, right?
Wow. So you know about that trick.
But no.
If you really want to undo
my curse, that isn't the way,
and this isn't the time.
Chase me, Guideau.
I'll give you signposts.
If you reach them all and catch up to me,
I'll live up to your expectations, too.
I forget how many decades it's been,
but let's pick up where we left off that day.
The Order must have caught on by now.
Oh, right. They can't
find me while I have this.
What a lucky find.
I mean, seriously...
You just never break, do you?
I swear, Angela...
I'll kill you if it's the last thing I do!
I like that look in your eyes.
Guideau!
Still breathing. Nothing to worry about.
You call that "nothing"?
She's hanging on by a thread.
As long as Guideau's breathing,
the rest works itself out.
Hey, what's that?
An Executioner!
We weren't gone long,
and I don't see any sign of a struggle.
Angela...
Who in the world is that witch?
A celebrity. You've heard of her, too.
Angela the Origin Witch.
That should be all you need to hear.
No way!
You mean the Angela?!
That can't be right!
There's no way she could still be alive!
Witches are destined to
only live for 200 years!
Oh, she's alive, all right.
The "Eternal Witch," Angela Anne Huell,
one of the world's most powerful witches,
continues to live on in it to this very day.
If that's true, Guideau chose one
hell of a person to pick a fight with.
You said it.
I suppose it was Angela
who carved those letters.
I see.
So it begins at last.
Guideau, are you awake?
I'm coming in.
Did you find her?
No, can't say I have.
Then get lost.
Why won't you touch your food?
Just look at you, still covered in wounds.
You eat and you heal, remember?
How could you starve yourself all this time?
If you won't eat, at least let me treat you.
Give me a look.
What kind of crap are
you gonna pull this time?
Back there, my arm and leg gave out on me...
because you did something
to them, didn't you?
Stop, Guideau.
You seem full of energy.
I guess you won't need healing.
You won't get another chance.
Try it again, and I won't wait
to undo the curse to kill you.
I'm sorry.
But I had no intention
of setting you up to fail.
I'm doing my best to
assure things go smoothly.
Nothing I do is pointless, and I won't
do anything against your interests.
You're a valuable human resource.
I would never do anything
that might result in losing you.
You understand that our interests align.
That's why you've obeyed my orders.
When you suspect I'm "pulling
something" in spite of that,
I'm only doing so for the sake
of the larger picture.
Let me repeat myself:
I'm not your enemy,
and I won't do anything to harm you.
I don't need your faith or trust.
For now, just understand that with your head.
Get out already.
Oh, I can't go anywhere until I heal up.
I have broken bones, you know.
Oh, that smarts.
Dear me, what a mess you've made.
This takes me back.
To three years ago, when we first met.
Lady Witch, would you return
to the Order with me?
Next time: "Eloquence
and Silence: Opening Act."
Eloquence and Silence
Opening Act