You're a valuable asset.
I would never do anything to jeopardize that.
You understand that our interests align.
That's why you've obeyed my orders.
When you suspect I'm
"pulling something" in spite of that,
know that it all fits into the bigger picture.
Let me repeat myself:
I'm not your enemy,
and I won't do anything to harm you.
I don't need your faith or trust.
For now, just understand that with your head.
Get out already.
Oh, I can't go anywhere until I heal up.
I have broken bones, you know.
Oh, so painful.
Dear me, what a mess you've made.
This takes me back.
To three years ago, when we first met.
Eloquence and Silence
Opening Act
A village on the Fifth Continent.
Being so far from the Global Holy Church's
headquarters on the First Continent,
a culture of magic has yet to develop here.
A remote, utterly un-magical village
in an ordinary, utterly un-magical land.
A coffin! Hey, that was a coffin, right?
Yes, yes. I'm sure it was.
It couldn't be less remarkable.
But this village is home to a witch.
She's apparently lived here a long time,
but until now, she's never caused a fuss.
Which explains why her presence
went unremarked upon.
But lately, it's been one
odd incident after another.
And finally, the fuss drew attention.
Given the circumstances,
I must secure the witch at once,
before someone turns up dead.
Let's go.
Well, this should do it for groceries.
Was there anything else we had to get?
Falvell, do you want anything?
Aw, come on. Don't hold back.
The latest batch of tea leaves and fabrics
were a hit, so the mayor paid us extra.
Treat yourself once in a while.
You there!
Look what you've gone and done!
What do you—
My cows!
Those were my cows!
I don't know what you mean!
We didn't touch them!
Hey, lay off. We've got no proof,
and the mayor's on her side.
You'll catch hell if you try anything.
Who else but a witch could've
done something like that?!
No human could've, that's for sure!
A crazy witch must've done it!
That's prejudice.
Ideas like that belong in the past, if you ask me.
Craig.
This is about what happened two days ago, right?
I didn't see it myself,
but I heard livestock fell from the sky.
Hm? Huh?
What the...
That's right. And in pieces, too.
Could a regular person do that?
I doubt it.
But the same goes for her.
She couldn't do something like that
in a million years, either.
What?! But she's a witch!
What makes this pair of monsters so different?!
Hi there. Pardon me.
I hate to butt in on a quarrel,
but yours involves someone I came here to see,
and your discussion piqued my interest.
Why do you say that she, a witch,
couldn't have done it?
Wh-Who are you?
Why? Because it's true.
Oh?
Everyone calls my big sister a witch,
but Falvell Farmington
can't cast a single spell!
Oh?
What?! You expect me to believe she's
innocent because she can't use magic?!
Anyone can make an excuse like that!
Hush now.
I'm afraid I must ask you to leave us.
Put him down.
Sure.
Go home.
All right.
Oh, are you single?
No, I've got a wife.
Me, too.
Is that so? Then shower them with love.
Why not buy some flowers on your way home?
Good idea. I'll do that.
Once in a while, you know?
Was that... magic?
Well, just a bit.
Yikes! Magic gives me the creeps!
Don't tell me you're behind everything?
I wonder.
Well, all joking aside...
It wasn't a joke!
Lady Witch, I'd like a word.
I've been looking for you.
I'm Ashaf. A first-rate mage, as you saw.
As you are a witch,
I have an earnest request for you.
Suspicious.
You're super shady, Mister.
But, well, you did help us out,
so I guess we need to repay you.
Hey, watch it.
You just bumped into me.
Are you listening?
Really, now?
I never thought I'd need three layers
against an unarmed opponent.
Move! You're in my way!
How fierce. What exactly am I in the way of?
Hand over that witch.
She's my prey.
What's wrong with people today?
What do you all want with Falvell?!
Remember this face?
Or this mark?!
That mark...
You have.
What's this freaky thing?
It vanished.
Did it protect her?
Did you see that?
What was that monster just now?
There she is.
The witch! The witch is right there!
Then that monster was...
Not good. People saw that.
What?
No. You're wrong!
Falvell didn't do anything!
She didn't!
We don't have parents.
The villagers don't treat us like people,
but the mayor's always been good to us.
Falvell uses plants from our garden and
the mountain out back for dye and tea,
and the mayor sells what
she makes to acquaintances.
Her stuff's popular.
Well, I'll be.
Surprisingly tasty, right?
It's the best tea I've ever had.
She can't use magic, but she says this is
part of the witch knowledge she inherited.
I see.
Would you care for a cup, too?
It tastes wonderful.
What a surprise.
I thought you'd be screaming at me to
remove the spell, but you're calm.
I guess you don't like to waste effort.
And I examined you
while you were unconscious,
but I found no signs of magical enhancement.
Yet you're tough enough to have barely
a scratch on you. And that brute strength...
You don't strike me as an ordinary human.
That mark on your neck.
It's the sign of a witch's curse, isn't it?
A witch's curse?
My guess is, you suspect this girl may have
a clue as to who cursed you.
Or that she herself is the culprit.
Why don't we start there?
But first, may I have a second cup?
Now, let me see. You are?
My name? Owent.
It's a pleasure, Owent.
I'd like your confirmation.
Falvell can't speak, can she?
No, she can't.
In our family, only the witches turn out that way.
They can't even make noises in their throats.
What? You told me she was sick.
Well, I mean, it's a weird story, right?
We just saw so many crazy things
that I figured I might as well come clean.
I see. And that is why she can't cast spells.
How much do you all know about magic?
Not much...
Thank you.
In that case, time for a lesson.
Generally speaking,
a person with magical energy
casts spells by tracing runes.
We either pour magic into pre-written runes,
or write runes using pure magical energy.
Let me treat you.
Listen, asshole—
She froze up?
Well, anyway...
As you can see,
lettering forms the basis of magic.
Spellcasting relies on
special letters called "runes."
But there are exceptions.
And Falvell, I suspect your
bloodline is one of them.
Its Origin: the "Mystic Witch,"
Luna Farmington.
A master of vocative magic
who cast all her spells with speech.
Invocation
But since you lack a voice,
you naturally can't make use of that magic.
For real?
You sure know a lot.
Do all mages know so much about witches?
I don't believe so.
And only a select few would
even know of the Mystic Witch.
Well?
Huh?
Falvell descends from the Mystic Witch.
Is that the witch who cursed you?
Her lineage doesn't mean shit.
The bitch I want can swap bodies.
Oh?
And you say she can't use magic?
Then what do you call
that thing that sent me flying?!
Yes, that's also an issue.
I'm not saying it presents a contradiction.
The problem is that we may have enemies here.
That creature was made
to look like Falvell's doing.
But Falvell can't use magic.
Working from that assumption,
someone must have orchestrated
it to appear that way.
Given how many people saw it,
if any more incidents occur,
all the blame will fall upon the "nefarious" witch.
Just to check, are there any local sorcerers?
No. Not even one.
I heard these bizarre events
started about a month ago.
Did any outsiders come through around then?
Not really.
Well, I guess I might count.
My dad and I moved here half a year ago.
Of course, neither of us can do magic, though.
Craig and his dad help us out!
They protect us like the mayor does!
No need to be so defensive.
I won't pounce on every suspect I find.
Half a year is too long ago. He's in the clear.
Hmm... No leads, then.
Our guest still doesn't seem convinced, either.
Are you scared?
A bestial woman,
a mysterious mage, the villagers...
You two are surrounded by too many enemies.
Do you have to spell it out like that?
Don't worry. I've come to
protect you from all of that.
Let me reintroduce myself.
I come from a group
by magic, for magic, and of magic:
the Order of Magical Resonance.
Lady Witch, would you return to the Order with me?
I'm back.
You're home late.
Hey! Are you drinking Falvell's tea again?
That's the last of it.
It's just so good, I can't help it.
Good thing I got some more.
Oh, that should keep us for a while.
Falvell ought to start charging us already.
We pay her, just not with money.
Oh, you won't believe what happened today.
What do you think?
I've never seriously
considered leaving the village.
It doesn't seem real.
I mean, can you imagine this hell ever ending?
Then again, what's to say things
will get better if we go?
To start with, that guy's really shady.
I don't trust a word he says.
I'll come back tomorrow.
Don't worry. We're used to having lots of enemies.
This is nothing new.
We'll get by somehow.
We always do.
That's how it's always been.
Hey, Falvell...
Do you trust him? That Ashaf guy?
Yeah. You're right.
Okay! I'll whip up something extra tasty tonight!
You can't understand it?
Sheltering a witch, you mean?
A witch with no magic is just dead weight.
What do you want her for?
Oh, so you believe she can't cast spells now?
If I get a good long look, I can
tell if that bitch is in there.
Is that so? I'm glad the girl's been exonerated.
But I wouldn't call her "dead weight."
Do you remember how she
reacted to seeing your mark?
It clearly rang a bell.
You forgot?
Maybe the hit that sent you flying
knocked a few memories loose, too.
If you ask me, we shouldn't
be surprised she recognized it.
She probably has a similar mark
somewhere on her own body.
Don't you find it strange?
Speech is the source of her magic.
And yet, only the witches
of their lineage lose their voices.
Couldn't be more contrived.
So, could she be under a type of curse, too?
Vocative magic boasts unparalleled power.
Perhaps another witch got scared
and sealed it away with a curse.
So what? That makes her even more useless.
A witch's curse is a pain in the—
True, it is a nuisance.
Undoing curses is a challenge.
Or it would be, if there
were only two ways to do it.
Hey! What do you know about—
Not now.
I hear a commotion across the way.
Craig!
What's all the fuss? What happened?
It came back!
That monster showed up again!
And then, the mayor...
How gruesome.
Her greatest benefactor, of all people.
Then we were right all along.
That girl is a devil.
We can't let her live!
And it gets worse!
An "expert witch hunter" showed up
to lead a mob to Falvell's house!
He had this weird mask on and...
An Executioner!
This is bad news!
I'll go with you!
That makes twice.
Executioners work in pairs.
You must be one of them.
That's all the proof you
needed to pull the trigger?
You said you'd cleared me,
but you suspected me this whole time.
Adults don't play fair.
What?
I want to teach you what love is.
Next time: "Eloquence and Silence: Final Act."
Eloquence and Silence
Final Act