An Executioner!
This really is bad news!
I'll go with you!
That makes twice.
Executioners work in pairs.
I take it you're one of them.
That's all the proof you
needed to pull the trigger?
You said you'd cleared me,
but you suspected me this whole time.
Adults don't play fair.
What?
Eloquence
and Silence
Final Act
Hi there.
Before you die,
tell me how to undo the curse.
You know something, don't you, jackass?
Given the circumstances, I suggest
offering to save me in exchange.
I've got no clue how to help you,
and I'm gonna kill you anyway.
Hurry up and tell me,
unless you want it to hurt.
That won't do at all.
Threats can't get you everything.
To get what you want,
you need to learn how to give, too.
Yap, yap, yap.
You sure don't know when to shut up.
There is a way to undo a witch's curse.
If you want to know what it is,
accept my terms.
Protect the girl. Protect Falvell.
You expect me to guard a witch?
You have to!
You'll never undo the curse without her!
Hi. You're home late.
I had hoped to at least
let you say your goodbyes.
Seize her.
But...
Don't worry. She won't resist.
You're rather late.
Did you kill Owent?
Yes. The villagers wouldn't listen to me.
Owent told me before he drew his last breath.
She can't use her power
because of a witch's curse.
Yes, there's the curse's mark.
Good grief.
We spent half a year investigating
in case she was hiding her power.
What a shame.
Undoing a witch's curse is beyond us.
I guess we can't steal Falvell's power, then.
Right. We'll just have to dispose of her.
I hate to lose the Mystic Witch's power,
but it is what it is.
But my biggest regret of all, Falvell,
is that I won't be able to
enjoy your tea anymore.
Sven, if you mind that much,
want to call off the execution?
Craig, when it comes to tea,
the last drop in the pot is always the best.
I've sheltered and supported you myself.
You're a stranger to mistrust,
my sweet, innocent Falvell.
I savored my days as your dear neighbor.
Now, more than anything,
I want to taste the last drop.
Stir up hatred against a witch and
toss everything she's got into a fire.
"Dispel evil with purifying flame"
or something like that, right?
You really stick to that
playbook of yours, Executioners.
What? I figured you had run away.
Craig, is this the woman
with the coffin you mentioned?
Yeah.
Well, now.
Don't tell me you came to protect Falvell?
Where did you come from?
How do you know how Executioners operate?
Just who are you?
Out of my way!
Get lost already!
A metal coffin?
Carrying this thing around
makes you stranger than ever.
What's inside it?
Well, the woman can wait.
I don't want anything
interrupting Falvell's execution.
What's wrong with you?! Run for it!
How irritating.
You couldn't possibly escape, could you?
Kind little Falvell could never leave
Owent and run, even if he is a corpse.
Do you hate me?
I've never seen you make that face before.
You can't possibly escape the
Executioners without magic.
I know I promised to protect you.
I'm sorry it turned out this way.
But Falvell, you're our only hope now.
Now, listen closely, understand?
Huh? What're you doing here?
How many times do I have
to tell you... to run for it?
To get what you want, you need to give.
Man, what a pain in the ass.
You hate those bastards, right?
I'll kick their asses for you.
So do what I say and get lost.
How will I undo this curse if you die on me?
You've seemed to be in pain since you got here.
As much as I hate to put you out of your
misery by dealing the coup de grâce...
What?
Who are you?!
Shit. I've gotten rusty.
Now there's a surprise.
I see. This means...
What are you all standing around for?!
Hurry up and grab the witch!
They're desperate to protect her!
Take her hostage!
That's right!
Quickly!
A hostage?
Like I give a shit.
I'm done with you.
I'll get revenge for you,
but protect your own damn self!
People, I command you:
don't move!
Huh?
I... I can't move a...
Fire, I command you:
go out.
What?
What's going on?
Oh, I see now.
So she has a witch's body, too.
By kissing a witch,
they undid each other's curses.
And you'd best brace yourself.
You're witnessing vocative magic.
A true rarity.
Everything in existence
is now hers to command.
Executioner...
W-Wait!
Don't be hasty, Falvell!
Stop, Falvell!
I command you...
Falvell!
Perish!
Talk about power.
Both Falvell...
and that monster.
Forget curses. Those were more like seals.
Damn it. The whole world's full of monsters.
No matter how many times I hear about
Falvell's magic, it still blows me away.
It's only a day later,
and I couldn't be healthier!
I'd say things worked out because
you only had a stopped heart.
"Only"?
Falvell's still a child.
When she grows up, I doubt even
the dead will be beyond her.
Now, what will you do?
As I already told you, kissing a witch
only undoes a curse temporarily.
And the power to dispel
curses dwells in purity,
which means it only works once per witch.
So that just leaves the conventional method.
You need to find the one who cursed you.
And the Order can teach you about witches
plus lots of other things you don't know.
So what will it be?
Lift the spell first, then.
What spell?
That weird broth you fed me.
I've been dying to have it
again for a while now.
What kind of spell was that?
Nothing I've eaten before
has ever made me feel like this.
You did something to my body!
Unless you've got a death wish, undo it now!
Do you mean you really can't tell?
Well, well. Dear me.
I see you have a lot you need to learn.
Huh?
Listen.
No spell or curse caused that
strange sensation you're feeling.
It's something everyone experiences.
Given the way you speak,
I can guess how you'd describe it.
Namely...
"It was damn tasty."
Guideau, you have a will of steel.
You'll never bend or soak up
others' ways of seeing things.
Your fierce sense of self can even
shake off magical brainwashing.
Even so, you've learned a lot
in the three years since we met,
and you've changed of your
own free will, albeit gradually.
Yet just one unfortunate meeting
has sent you right back to that day.
Angela Anne Huell.
What a despicable witch.
I'm not fully recovered,
but I can more or less move now.
I have faith that what we've
built up hasn't crumbled,
and that this was just
a temporary outburst.
I still have something I want
to teach you more than anything.
Wait.
What does that mean?
Do you imagine I'm still keeping
useful information from you?
It's nothing like that.
Love, Guideau.
I want to teach you what love is.
I assume you know that
our world has eight continents.
The world's most influential
organization, the Global Holy Church,
has its headquarters on the First Continent.
First Continent
The Second Continent lies east
of that, followed by the Third.
Second Continent
Third Continent
The farther you go from the progenitor
of magic, the Global Holy Church,
the lower the level of
magical civilization grows.
But the Eighth Continent,
the farthest from the First,
flourishes through its
own distinctive sorcery.
You live on the Seventh Continent,
but you likely find it quite comfortable,
thanks to having the Eighth next door.
Well, that aside...
This world of ours also
includes a few anomalous areas.
Like the isolated island between
the Seventh and Eighth continents.
It has a hole in it.
A bottomless pit.
You might think,
"Where that pit leads, no one knows."
But not in the least.
That question has already
been thoroughly answered.
You can even book a tour, if you like.
Although for that,
you'd need privilege, wealth,
and the resolve to risk your life.
The Order has all three,
so we got approval.
This is the entrance to a hole
out of this world: the Fall.
(Tiered Worlds)
The Fall
We appreciate your visit, Mr. Ashaf.
Please proceed to your right.
The Fall has seventeen levels.
Each one connects to a
different, independent world.
The letters Angela carved
into that Executioner...
are part of a writing system from the Fall.
To outsiders, this is the only
place that comes to mind.
If we're going to pursue Angela,
we should find her or another clue here.
Welcome to Level Four.
Or the final floor leading
to Level Four, to be precise.
This level can be rather dangerous.
Even more so if its residents
recognize you as travelers.
This floor offers services
including changes of wardrobe
and local coordinators
well-versed in the level's customs.
No, thank you.
Show us to the dressing rooms.
What may I do for you?
Let me see...
We'd prefer middle-class outfits,
and we'd like to visit
upper-class venues, as well.
Certainly, sir.
Give us outfits for ten days,
plus a few spares.
That will be a lot to carry.
I'll prepare a servant and carriage, as well.
Or will you store them in that bag?
No, I'd like the carriage for this coffin.
As you guessed, my case can fit most things,
but this has too much mass to compress.
Understood.
And one last request.
We'd like some all-black outfits.
Several sets of those, too.
Um, wearing all black on this level signals...
Oh, don't worry.
I know.
Please wait a few moments, then.
Now we're ready.
How does your outfit feel?
Who cares? It's just cloth.
It's all the same as long as I can tear it up.
You will, of course,
keep it all clean and intact.
In that case, it's a pain
in the ass to move in.
Comfort aside, it suits you to a T.
That said...
You'll have no shortage of chances
to ruin your clothes in this world.
Now, shall we go?
Level Four: Orlencia Sett.
A world where vampires dwell.